I hate the IRS

Day 00360: Tuesday, 2016 March 01

I checked on that envelope sent to me the other day by the IRS. I had assumed that this envelope contained my tax refund check from the federal government, but this was not the case at all. Instead, it was a 5071C letter informing me that the IRS was rejecting my tax return until I verified my identity. I was given thirty days to do so, but I had lost five days due to not having opened the letter right away. The letter said that I had two ways to verify my identity. I could either do it online at idverify.irs.gov or I could do it by telephone. Of course, by telephone is no way to do anything, so I went with the Web option. After entering my information, the site said that they couldn't verify my identity online. My guess is that the reason that they are demanding this verification and the reason that they are rejecting my attempt to comply is one and the same. They are probably hating on me for using Tor or for not providing a telephone number. There is no law requiring that I have telephone service though, so they cannot demand that of me. Furthermore, they are not providing any reason for the rejection, so I cannot just assume that their hatred of Tor and privacy is the issue. I couldn't find an appropriate way to contact them about the issue. I ended up using a questions and comments form to post this:

I have received a 5071C letter asking me to verify my identity, either online or by telephone. However, the online form says that I cannot verify online and does not give me a reason why not. I do not have telephone service, so verification by telephone is not possible. What do you want me to do?

I thought about going over to the community college for help tomorrow. I saw some mention of a tax help service there. I quickly dismissed the idea though, realizing that the school would probably take the easy way out, having me use their telephone to perform the call. It wasn't until a bit later that it hit me: it's okay if I call from the school. It's suboptimal to be stuck using a telephone at all, as it validates dependency on the telephone number system. However, it's not calling from a number belonging to me, so it has nothing to do with my identity, and it's calling from a number that is semi-public. They can lock down what city I'm in, but cannot lock that number down as being me. I'll provide them the information that they ask for, but I will not have my identity locked to an idiotic telephone number. Furthermore, it would show that I am attempting to comply with their ridiculous demands. I am not fighting them, I simply do not have telephone service. I will not go tomorrow though. the form that I filled out said to wait 48 hours for a response, so that's just what I'll do. After that, I'll go over to the school.

My mother has requested that I attempt to contact the garbage company and the cable company that service our old residence tomorrow and have them email her all her past bills from 2008 January up through now. I tried to work on that tonight, but as I was logging into the cable company website, they took it down for maintenance. I was able to reach the garbage company website, but they don't seem to have an online interface for speaking with them or managing your account. I submitted a request through their asyncronous contact form, but I don't know how quickly that they will respond.

I tried to get help with cjdns today, and I was told to install nodejs-dev and nodejs-legacy. This alleviated part of the problem, and allowed me to move on past the initial snag, but there seemed to be another snag. I later went back to try again, and ran into the initial snag once more. I might try further tomorrow.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Letters from the IRS

Day 00361: Wednesday, 2016 March 02

I've run into an issue with normalizing IRC URIs. When I originally was looking through the documents on URI schemes, I was looking for default ports. I also assumed that the documents were consistent. However, this is not the case at all. The official document that introduces the irc: scheme as provisional specified the scheme syntax as "irc://<host>[:<port>]/[<channel>[?<password>]]". It cites three documents as references: a Wikipedia article, an expired draft by Simon Butcher, and an expired draft by Mandar Mirashi. Wikipedia says that the scheme syntax is "irc://<host>[:<port>]/[<channel>[?<channel_keyword>]]". Assuming that "channel keyword" means "password needed to access the channel", that means that the official provisional scheme document used the format from Wikipedia. However, neither provide information on the default port number. Additionally, the two drafts use different syntaxes than the scheme registration document and Wikipedia, and even use different syntaxes than one another. The two draft documents even specify different default port numbers. I had been using Butcher's draft, as it was the only reference mentioned in the document registering the ircs: URI. However, the draft's syntax doesn't match the ircs: scheme registration either. At least as there is only one reference mentioned in this registration, I can at least assume that the default port from the referenced draft, but I don't feel safe doing that because the syntax doesn't match. Why would the default port number be accurate? This is a mess now that I actually take a better look. I need to once again fix all the ircs: URIs on both my sites to make them match the actual registered syntax. As for my URI normalization classes, I'm not sure I can properly implement port normalization, as I can't be sure what port to normalize *to*, and I'm not sure if I should try to handle all three syntaxes or just the registered one. I can't help but feel that this lack of usable data is Microsoft's fault. Some Microsoft lackey went through and registered a bunch of in-use schemes, including but not limited to irc:, irc6:, and ircs:, and didn't even bother to actually provide complete information about the schemes. I think I'll use a mixed syntax for attempting to parse URIs for their components. I'll then normalize to the format specified in the scheme registration document. If any syntax-dependent components from one of the drafts is used in a given URI and that URI does not specify a port, the default port from that draft will be added. No port numbers will be removed, as I'm not sure a reliable default port number is available.

I set up the classes for the https: and http: first, only to realize that I should have started with the gopher:, telnet:, and tn3270: classes first. The telnet: and tn3270: schemes are pretty obscure, but Gopher can link to them, so these classes will be needed for the updated Gopher directory-parsing function. I started work on the class for normalizing URIs of the gopher: scheme, but ran out of time.

I managed to get ahold of both the garbage company and the cable company. The garbage company was more than happy to help, but for security reasons, said that they would send the bills to the email address on file instead of my mother's new email address. It turns out that the cable company's website is pretty messed up. I'm not sure if it's actually due to maintenance though. Using a different URI, you can actually access the account. However, my mother's account is somehow not the primary account, so it's unable to access past bills. I brought up a chat with a representative, but the representative was unable to help either. She said that the account wasn't the primary one, and said that only my mother, the account holder, could authorize me or the account to access the past bills. She tried to call my mother, but my mother couldn't pick up the telephone because she was at work. Furthermore, the cable company doesn't keep records beyond a year, or so the representative claims, so even once my mother handled the issue, she wouldn't be able to retrieve all the records that she was looking for.

When my mother got home, she was angry that i had not tried to reach her at work and explain the situation. However, the cable company had already tried to reach her. As she was unreachable, it didn't make sense for me to also try to reach her.

Tomorrow, my mother and I will head to Springfield for a few hours. She will be going to court while I will be working on cleaning up our old residence.

The IRS wrote back. (I have redacted my email address due to it containing my legal name. If you want my legal name, you'll have to put in the minimal effort required to find my DNS domain name from the foot of this Web page and run a whois query on it. I've also redacted the survey access key, as I don't need people filling out the survey on my behalf.)

Please use the ticket number located in the subject line of this email in any correspondence with the IRS

SUBJECT: Comment from Web Site sent to irs.gov.website.helpdesk@speedymail.com

Dear [REDACTED]@y.st,

Thank you for contacting the IRS.gov Website Help Desk.

The purpose of the IRS Website Help Desk is to assist with navigational questions about IRS.gov. We do not have access to specific tax related information.

We are here to assist with finding content on the IRS.gov website. Please refer to the link below for information applicable to your inquiry.

I do apologize but at this time contact by telephone would be your only option. Please refer to the link below for the number to call

https://www.irs.gov/uac/Telephone-Assistance

For additional website assistance or information, you may insert a few words or phrases relating to your inquiry into the &#8216;Search&#8217; field located at the top right hand corner (blue area) of our Web page. You may also review our 'Frequently Asked Questions' or 'Tax Topics' Web pages.

We appreciate your visit to our website and invite you to visit us for your future tax needs.

I would like to know what you thought about your email experience. Please click the survey link (http://research.affina.com/snapwebhost/surveylogin.asp?k=[REDACTED]) to complete our online customer satisfaction survey.

Sincerely,

The IRS.gov Web Site Help Desk

I was not amused. They had completely ignored the fact that I don't have telephone service and asked that I call anyway. I then proceeded to have an email discussion with them in which I couldn't get any reasonable information from them unless I focused on one detail at a time.

As I said before, I cannot contact you by telephone. Telephone is not an option, because I have no telephone service.

You said that you could help with navigation of the website. Can you please help me find the section of the website that provided non-telephone methods of contacting the IRS about these matters? There doesn't seem to be any obvious way to find the contact information.

Please use the ticket number located in the subject line of this email in any correspondence with the IRS.

SUBJECT: Comment from Web Site sent to irs.gov.website.helpdesk@speedymail.com

Dear [REDACTED]@y.st,

Thank you for contacting the IRS.gov Website Help Desk.

The purpose of the IRS Website Help Desk is to assist with navigational questions about IRS.gov. We do not have access to specific tax related information.

I do apologize but at this time contact by telephone would be your only option. Please refer to the link below for the number to call

https://www.irs.gov/uac/Telephone-Assistance

I would like to know what you thought about your email experience. Please click the survey link (http://research.affina.com/snapwebhost/surveylogin.asp?k=[REDACTED]) to complete our online customer satisfaction survey.

Sincerely,

The IRS.gov Web Site Help Desk

I cannot call a telephone number. I have no telephone service. What do you want me to do?

Please use the ticket number located in the subject line of this email in any correspondence with the IRS.

SUBJECT: Comment from Web Site sent to irs.gov.website.helpdesk@speedymail.com

Dear [REDACTED]@y.st,

Thank you for contacting the IRS.gov Website Help Desk.

The purpose of the IRS Website Help Desk is to assist with navigational questions about IRS.gov. We do not have access to specific tax related information.

We are here to assist with finding content on the IRS.gov website. Please refer to the link below for information applicable to your inquiry. Please click on your state or if you are out of the country please click international.

https://www.irs.gov/uac/Contact-Your-Local-IRS-Office-1

For additional website assistance or information, you may insert a few words or phrases relating to your inquiry into the ‘Search’ field located at the top right hand corner (blue area) of our Web page. You may also review our 'Frequently Asked Questions' or 'Tax Topics' Web pages.

We appreciate your visit to our website and invite you to visit us for your future tax needs.

I would like to know what you thought about your email experience. Please click the survey link (http://research.affina.com/snapwebhost/surveylogin.asp?k=[REDACTED]) to complete our online customer satisfaction survey.

Sincerely,

The IRS.gov Web Site Help Desk

You say that you can assist with navigational questions. Can you please help me navigate to the section of the website that provides email addresses at which to reach the IRS? Also, in one of the surveys, I saw that the IRS has a live chat option. Can you please help me find the page where that is located?

Thank you.

The IRS is really making me angry. I haven't heard back yet, but maybe I will get a straight answer with that last question. I know that it's a long shot, but I can hope.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Addressed to the Stars

Day 00363: Friday, 2016 March 04

Before heading out yesterday, I found this letter in my inbox:

Please use the ticket number located in the subject line of this email in any correspondence with the IRS.

SUBJECT: Comment from Web Site sent to irs.gov.website.helpdesk@speedymail.com

Dear [REDACTED]@y.st,

Thank you for contacting the IRS.gov Website Help Desk.

The purpose of the IRS Website Help Desk is to assist with navigational questions about IRS.gov. We do not have access to specific tax related information.

We are here to assist with finding content on the IRS.gov website. Please refer to the link below for information applicable to your inquiry about the Live chat room. Please note that the IRS does not maintain a live chat or email address regarding specific tax related information.

https://www.irs.gov/uac/Navigate-IRSgov

I do apologize but due to the notice you have for verifying your identity, there are two options. The first one is to use the website provided in your notice to verify your identity, or the other option would be to do it by phone. I understand you are unable to reach them by telephone. In this case you may want to visist your local IRS office in person and discuss concern with a agent.

For additional website assistance or information, you may insert a few words or phrases relating to your inquiry into the &#8216;Search&#8217; field located at the top right hand corner (blue area) of our Web page. You may also review our 'Frequently Asked Questions' or 'Tax Topics' Web pages.

We appreciate your visit to our website and invite you to visit us for your future tax needs.

I would like to know what you thought about your email experience. Please click the survey link (http://research.affina.com/snapwebhost/surveylogin.asp?k=144898929474) to complete our online customer satisfaction survey.

Sincerely,

The IRS.gov Web Site Help Desk

I couldn't really go in person because the IRS doesn't have any offices in my town or the adjacent town. I'm a pedestrian and there is no legal requirement that I own or know how to drive a vehicle. The website mentioned had been telling me that I couldn't verify my identity online and using a telephone and encouraging the moronic telephone number system was out of the question. Again, there's no legal requirement that I have a telephone line, so government agencies such as the IRS cannot demand that I do anything by telephone. The letter did mention how to get to the live chat page though, which much to my embarrassment, was right on the same page as the initial form that I had used to initiate this email conversation. There was no time to act on this yesterday though, as the entire span of time that the live chat sessions are available during a day, I was in Springfield.

I came up with three plans on what to do about the IRS. The first plan was stupid and counterproductive on several levels. I made it while I was still pretty angry, so I'll just leave it out. The second idea was to attempt to refile via postal mail, including a copy of my Social Security card and photographic ID, a copy of their letter to me, and a letter to them explaining the situation, saying that if they would not allow me to prove my identity over the Web and did not accept my mailed-in identity documents as proof, I did not know what else to do and they would need to make accommodations. I would assert that as there is no law saying that I am required to have telephone service, they cannot demand that I use a telephone to perform this mandatory identity verification. I would then conclude saying that as they do not have an office in my city or the neighboring city, and because I am not a driver, I cannot reach them in person, but if they want to reach me in person, they are welcome to send someone to my house. If they send someone over, I would be more than happy to answer any identifying questions that they have and show them original copies of my identity documents. The third plan was the most simple, and in my opinion, the best: I would simply wait it out. The IRS said that if I didn't verify my identity to them within thirty days, they would throw out the tax filing information that I had sent them. I'd check the data in which that happened, then simply re-file using the exact same information. If they demanded verification again but wouldn't allow me to comply without a telephone, I would file for an extension (seeing as the tax-filing deadline would be past), then continue waiting and submitting until they accepted my tax documents.

Of course, all of this planning was only in case the IRS people manning the live chat session refused to help. I started the live session today, and the representative seemed to understand my problem, but didn't have any information on what to do about it. As the representative had mentioned using the online verification at one point, I decided to attempt verification again to get a screenshot, which I should have taken two days ago. However, much to my embarrassment again, the verification site functioned without issue this time. I apologized to the representative and explained that the verification site had quit denying my verification.

This time, the verification site asked some random multiple-choice questions of me that it had not before, such as the address of my former residence. The verification site mentioned using a third-party site to acquire such questions and their answers, so perhaps that third-party website was down before. If that is the case, it means that the IRS is not guilty of both failing to provide helpful error messages and maliciously discriminating against Tor users; they are just guilty of failing to provide helpful error messages. In other words, they are idiots. All that they would have had to do is have their error message state that there were technical difficulties and that the user should try back later. Instead, they said that I couldn't verify online, not even mentioning that it was a temporary problem. I am now only mildly annoyed with the IRS. I can handle idiots a lot better than I can handle those that attack the Internet by, for example, discriminating against Tor exit nodes.

One of my flashes of inspiration yesterday was about Ricochet. I tried in the past and failed to get Ricochet to make use of the onion address provided by the system's Tor daemon. But what if I could do the reverse? What if I allowed Ricochet to be over-controlling and manage the onion address itself? If it could just forward the ports to my other services, they could all share the onion just fine. I wouldn't be able to get two over-controlling services to share an onion address, but I would be able to make one share with permissive services and those that are unaware of Tor. I broke out my key for nfcbk2sgyblvdnq3.onion. and started testing. However, I wasn't able to actually set this up. It seems that the Tor configuration used by Ricochet is actually built into the binary; it isn't a separate file. I found the relevant line in the source code, but they aren't a plain-text configuration file, they are in the form of function calls and objects. I'm not sure how to properly modify it to have it open up other onion ports for other services. I also tried onion port forwarding from the system Tor daemon to Ricochet again, but like before, that didn't work. I also tried adding HiddenServicePort 80 127.0.0.1:80 to {Ricochet directory}/config/tor/torrc, then to {Ricochet directory}/config/tor/default_torrc, but in both cases, Tor didn't properly start. Ricochet then couldn't connect to the network. The error message made sense, [warn] HiddenServicePort with no preceding HiddenServiceDir directive, but I'm not sure how to get around it. I'm not sure if the problem is that these files are parsed before Ricochet adds its onion address or if the problem is that they are a separate file than the one that defines the HiddenServiceDir. I could test, but I didn't think of that until I was writing my weblog entry and heading off to bed. Either way though, it wouldn't fix the issue. It's also worth noting that Ricochet also fails to add its onion and fails to connect to the network if you make the permissions on its hidden service directory too permissive.

Another idea of mine from yesterday was to use mod_rewrite to fix malformed SNI host names in order to allow Apache to accept invalid SNI host names without throwing an error. The main purpose of this would be to set up a test page that checked Web browsers to see if they were sending both the correct Host header and correct SNI host name. Mod_rewrite didn't work the way I needed it to though, and I'm reasonably certain that what I'm trying to accomplish isn't possible.

Josh Woodward is about to release a new album, Addressed to the Stars. He posted his new album on Kickstarter, and as usual, he's quickly surpassed his funding goal. He doesn't really ask for as much as his work is worth and his fans sure do love to throw money at him! At the $44 USD tier, he'll send you a copy of both this album and an early version of another album he's working on, as well as your name in the credits of his liner notes, so I went with that option. Hopefully I can talk him into using my URI in place of my name, or at the very least, get him to use my real name instead of my legal name (he does know the latter).

In an article about the harm caused by discrimination against Tor users, which is ironically blocked by CloudFlare, I learned some disturbing news. Tor users can be maliciously blocked not only at the application layer level, but at the TCP level! I've run across several websites in search results that seem to no longer exist. I've wondered why these sites are still in search results instead of being weeded out by the search engines when attempting a recrawl. Now I know. The sites only appear down from my end because of this devious form of anti-privacy block.

I started setting up a mirror of Ronsor's website, but I had to set that aside fro tonight. As a little exercise, I set my server to recognize the ".html" and ".htm" file extensions, the two that he used for pages of his site, as XHTML. If his markup was clean, it would have worked with little modification. However, there were some sloppy-yet-valid-in-HTML parts, such as use of unquoted values. I tried to talk to Ronsor about fixing these, but he didn't go for it, stating that it wasn't meant to be served as XHTML. I had even offered to do the fixing my self if he wanted and send him the changes! Not that he knew it, but I wasn't planning to fully convert his site to XHTML, but I was going to clean up the code. While waiting for his response, I had cleaned up the first page, and found something that someone more knowledgeable than I would already know, but which was interesting to me: even with the code cleaned up syntactically, it did not display as a Web page when sent as XHTML. To make the Web browser recognize it as a Web page, I needed to set the xmlns attribute. This would have been something that I fix on my end but not include in the fix that I sent him, as he had clearly not intended to use XHTML. I may have gotten nowhere in getting him to accept cleaner code or clean the code himself, but learning that xmlns is necessary for more than validity was worth the minor amount of effort, so I'd say the experiment was a success.

I have now received a third letter from the health care people, and I now think that I have all the necessary information for making use of my coverage. Why did they send it in three parts? It would have saved envelopes and postage to include all of the information at once. They could have waited to send anything until they had all the necessary information themselves. In any case, it seems that my health care provider is Western Oregon Advanced Health, a place on the far side of the city from me. It's practically two cities away, given the strange layout of the town. I have to pass through North Bend, then back into Coos Bay from another angle in order to reach it. Being a pedestrian, this means going in to see a doctor will be an all-day affair. At least I'm meating the government's ridiculous requirements though.

For a good chunk of the day, we went to the nearby beach with the sinky sand. This time, I made sure to stay far enough from the water that the land was fairly stable, as did Cyrus. My mother and Vanessa on the other hand went out and sank. After that, Cyrus went home and Vanessa, our mother, and I went to gather more bullet shells.

A thought just occurred to me. When I was using OX X, years ago before I discovered freedom, I built a Web interface for manipulating chicken's files with. Again, this was back before chicken was chicken. Now, I use SSH and SFTP. It's built nearly-seamlessly into my desktop! But when did I start using SSH? How did I find out about it? I can't remember ever using SSH on OS X, but I also cannot remember using my Web interface on Ubuntu (Ubuntu was my first Linux distribution, again, before I found freedom).

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Relay service

Day 00364: Saturday, 2016 March 05

I did not sleep well last night. I woke up at about four and couldn't get back to sleep.

I began my onion-to-clearnet forwarding service today to aid in bypassing Tor blocks. I obviously can't use it myself, as my own IP address acts as the exit, but perhaps someone can make use of it. Unfortunately, I set up the website for the server over HTTP instead of HTTPS. I much prefer HTTPS, but a lot of onionlanders don't. This service is for them, not me, and encryption is already supplied by Tor, so I'll do it their way. I've also decided to use the high ports, not the low ports, for forwarding. Many of the low ports have specific services that they are assumed to run. If I end up needing one of those ports after I've already assigned it for forwarding, it will be too late. As such, I've decided to use the ports in the 49152-65535 range, as they are currently defined as ports that will not be assigned any specific service. If the IANA decides to change this, some network changes will be to be expected, so there won't be any issues with me reclaiming ports; it wasn't my fault, I took reasonable precautions. Wowaname suggested allowing other people to share their IP addresses in the same way, using my onion to forward to random volunteer machines in a round-robin-type way. I'm not sure who would volunteer, but it seems like it would be easy to set up on their end. The simplest way would probably be to set up port forwarding in their home router configuration. They wouldn't even need to install Tor, though of course I recommend installing and using Tor to everyone. I thought about adding freenode to my forwarding configuration, but due to the fact that I don't want to play "favorites" with Tor-haters, I didn't want to add any specific services until they were requested. Ronsor quickly suggested freenode (once people were actually awake), so that resolved that issue.

While discussing ways to get multiple IP addresses to be usable for relay service, wowaname and I were discussing on #Volatile how nice round robin support for onion addresses. One hidden service node can relay to multiple servers, but multiple hidden service nodes cannot use the same onion address like can be done in DNS. Cathugger knew of an article about horizontal scalability of hidden services. With the techniques the author suggests, it is possible to get up to sixty separate machines at separate locations to receive requests meant for a single onion address. These sixty machines are all registered with the Tor network without any changes to the underlying infrastructure. The only things changed are on the machines that hold the private onion key. It sounds a bit difficult to deploy and custom code is needed, but it might get people thinking about the need to share onion addresses between machines like this. It might lead to changes in how Tor fundamentally handles hidden services. Even if it doesn't lead to changes, it provides an option for large services that really need more room to grow on the Tor network.

When the local community college said that they would send me a gift card, I assumed that it was a use-anywhere prepaid type of gift card. That was a naïve assumption on my part. The card arrived in the mail today and it's a gift card for their in-house book store. As the card dosen't have much on it and I don't know if I'll be attending this school, it's little more than an amusing novelty item. Still, it got me to submit my feedback for their orientation. I was going to do that anyway, but this helped make sure I did it in a timely manner.

Our mother, Cyrus, Vanessa, and I volunteered at a spaghetti-serving fund raiser today. We told them that we were there to help, then waited a couple hours for them to be ready for help. We were pretty much just wasting time unable to do anything, so we asked if they even needed us. They told us that they didn't even want our help. Why didn't they just tell us that from the beginning? While I was waiting, I thought about the fact that my accessed574tizbu onion would have been a cool address for my forwarding service because it helps people access malicious servers, but I'm going to continue using my sbuk7aqcxkoyipwv onion.

It seems that Ronsor will be away for three weeks.

Wowaname decided that she wanted her Tor-to-IRC2P onion to be "listed" on my forwarding service. It seemed pretty strange to me. I'm not sure she understood that it was a forwarding service, not a listing of forwarding services. However, it seemed like it could be of benefit to Tor users, as it does provide access to a service not normally reachable over Tor, so I went with it. However, I didn't want it to look like my forwarding service was not up to forwarding to other darknets and that this burden had to fall to others. To fix this, I set up I2P on my server and forwarded one of my onion ports to IRC2P as well. If I chance upon any other services similar to mine, I'll add them to my list and forward to their destinations in parallel. A little redundancy doesn't hurt. While the onion-to-clearnet ports are nice for getting access to places without giving into their ridiculous anti-privacy agendas, the onion-to-other-darnet ports are nice for convenience.

As I was installing I2P on my server, I decided to install it from a package, unlike on my client machine. Installation went fine, but I found that I2P's package, being from a non-Debian party, is not set up to start itself as a system service. You still need to run i2prouter start to start it each time you start the system, unless you script something to take care of that. I2P's strange (in my opinion) setup of binding ports to services made it ridiculously easy to forward between darknets. It also didn't hurt that one of the default port bindings was pointed directly to the service that I needed in this case.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Disillusioned with onion addresses

Day 00365: Sunday, 2016 March 06

A thought just occurred to me. I no longer need to avoid mentioning freenode entirely when I write about things that have happened there. I just need to be sure to use the link to my own forwarding onion address when making such mentions. I still can't use this onion address to connect, as it would be identical to not using Tor to connect at all, but other people can without struggling with freenode's incomplete Tor blocks. Also, removed my relay to IRC2P, as it only serves to distract from wowaname's relay, and instead decided to add as many Tor-blocking networks as I know of before being asked. They might be useful to someone, but someone may be too timid to ask. I know I would be. Each day, the plan was to try to add at least one IRC network that's present in the default HexChat server list, until I reach the end of the list. I've uninstalled I2P from the server as well, as it no longer serves a purpose on that machine.

I started testing IRC servers and adding them to both my torrc file and my XHTML list of port that are forwarded, but I quickly found keeping them in sync to be bothersome. To fix this, I built a function that could parse a hidden service block from a Tor configuration file and format it as the list that I was after. I needed to be able to tell the parser which URI scheme to use for a given item (ircs: or irc:), as well as make my parser generic enough to handle other use cases, so I included a comment syntax that tells it what scheme to use. Making it more generic also required that I remove some IRC-specific information, but I have to reluctantly admit that the result looks a lot cleaner.

That ended up being in vain though. I found a couple issues in Tor that prevent me from forwarding as many ports as I would like to. The first problem is that some of the domain names I'm trying to forward to are supposedly unparseable, though I can't see anything wrong with the four domains that cause the issue. This error shows up in the error log: Mar 06 21:56:58.930 [warn] Unparseable address in hidden service port configuration.. After commenting out the offensive lines, I run into a bug: *** Error in `tor': free(): invalid pointer: 0x00007fde87a055c0 ***. This pointer error only happens if I forward several ports, and even then, there isn't stable number of forwarded ports. With few enough ports forwarded, the pointer error never occurs, and with enough forwarded, it always occurs. However, somewhere in the middle, the error only sometimes occurs. I can start Tor, it'll shut down because of that error, then I'll start it a second time and there'll be no problems. The only option that i can see is to comment out all the lines that haven't been requested and go back to only forwarding ports on demand. That way, I have the ports to spare when a new request is made and I'm not wasting ports on services that people aren't even using. This experience has left me a bit disillusioned with onion addresses. If I can't even make use of all my ports like can be done with a DNS address, this really cuts down on their usefulness. I imagine this limitation applies to the sum total of ports forwarded by all onion addresses used by a given Tor instance, especially because it's caused by an error, so setting up extra hidden services wouldn't likely even help.

On #Volatile, z showed us an awesome website that is working to free knowledge from the clutches of those that would hide it behind pay walls. I'm not sure how they operate, but it's wonderful to see such work being done.

We went over to my mother's school to help her only to find out that she didn't want or need any help. So what was the point? We were there for three hours with nothing to do. Next time, I'm bringing my laptop just in cast this sort of thing happens again. I could have been doing something productive with my time.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Onion addresses are fixed in a more recent version of Tor

Day 00366: Monday, 2016 March 07

Josh Woodward wrote back today. He said that I couldn't use a URI, but didn't comment on using a name other than my legal name. Hopefully, the fact that my credit card is issued under my preferred name instead of my legal name will get him to allow me to use my preferred name.

Further testing of Tor led me to some interesting new information about the bugs I ran into yesterday. And yes, it tuns out that the "unparseable address" issue was a second bug. The bug is in the error messages though. Instead of being unparseable, the addresses are actually *unresolvable*. Four of the addresses are outdated and no longer exist in DNS. Instead of Tor saying that they can't be resolved, it says they cannot be parsed. Second, it seems that if I tell Tor to forward to IP addresses instead of DNS names, the pointer error goes away. I can forward as many ports as I like as long as I use numbers instead of names! It's of course suboptimal because IP addresses are more likely to change than domain names, but at least it allows me to make full use of my onion address.

On #Tor, I mentioned the fact that using IP addresses instead of fixed the pointer error that I had mentioned yesterday, but that no one had cared about at the time. This time though, with new information, it piqued arma's interest. Arma wanted me to test on a much newer version of Tor though, as the Debian version is eleven months old. I usually prefer to use packages from the Debian repository, but I added the Tor repository anyway and upgraded. This lead to another issue: the newer version of Tor claimed that my file system was read-only, so it couldn't properly interact with my hidden service directories. As it turns out, the new version of Tor refuse to use hidden service directories that are outside of /var/lib/tor/, but again, returns an incorrect error message. Weasel said that Tor resolves each domain name to a single IP address when Tor starts, which is a bit of a drag. It means that when a domain name has multiple A records, only one will be used. Then again though, arma also said that Tor doesn't have a round robin feature and that there is no point in trying to map one onion port to multiple destinations. However, as wowaname pointed out, the round robin feature is actually documented in the manual (man tor). With the new version of Tor seeming to function fine for onion port forwarding, I finished testing IRC networks and setting up port forwards. I also refined my torrc file parser a bit more to clean up the output further. I need to get that function released at some point, but I'll probably put it off until the next unrelated update of include.d.

I had planned to walk to my health care provider today. It would have been an all-day affair given how far they are from me, but it would have given me a chance to time the trip. Before I can schedule any appointments, I need to know how long before an appointment I should head out. However, I decided to put that off for a while. It turned out to be useful that I stayed at home. My IRS check came today when I would have been out, so I took it down to the bank to start an account.

When I went down there, there was a huge line. Today was the first day in which this branch was officially Bank of the Cascades instead of Bank of America; it had caused a lot of confusion. At least one person was there to close her account because her account had been sold when the branches were, but she didn't want to transfer to Bank of the Cascades. She wanted her Bank of America account back. Another person had been on vacation, so he didn't get the email about his Bank of America debit card soon being canceled and the fact that he needed to activate a new Bank of the Cascades debit card. He got a nasty surprise when he tried to charge to his card. I found though that the savings accounts that they offer have a fairly low minimum balance for avoiding fees: $100 USD. I can only withdraw money a maximum of three times per month before dealing with fees, but I don't withdraw that often, and if for some reason I needed more money, I could start withdrawing in larger increments. As usual, the low-ranking bank representatives thought that having a telephone number was mandatory, but after speaking with their bosses to see if there was a workaround for this because I don't have telephone service, found that the workaround is to simply leave the telephone number field blank when entering my information into their computer system. A telephone number is not in any way needed, as usual.

Whitanne_, from #Volatile, said that I should add an RSS feen to my weblog. I suppose when I have time, I'll try to set that up. I don't know the RSS format though, so it might take a while. Hopefully, I'll be able to set up a script to update the feed automatically.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

RSS feed coded, but postponed

Day 00368: Wednesday, 2016 March 09

It just occurred to me today: if Tor no longer allows hidden service directories outside of /var/lib/tor/, won't that break TorChat and Ricochet? I asked in #Tor, and arma assured me that this isn't the case. The new Tor packages use an apparmor profile. Supposedly, this will not interfere with TorChat or Ricochet's use of Tor to store hidden service directories in more accessible places. If this is true, I can only assume that it means that the apparmor profile is used by the service, as the TorChat package uses the Tor system package, and thus the main Tor binary.

I wrote to my ond school about the expired check I found yesterday, but they told me to call the school and ask by telephone instead. I wrote back explaining that I haven't had telephone service for about ten months, then asked if there was a way to get the information I'm looking for without a telephone. I'll probably see how they respond tomorrow.

Wowaname was talking about KindOne being able pay for the VPS any more, so I assumed that the VPS had become too costly. However, it seems that there wasn't a funding problem, but a login problem. The log in password has been lost, so KindOne wasn't able to log in to pay the bill. I know how that feels. I lost a few domain names that way.

I built the code to build my RSS feed for my weblog, but I can't find the XML namespace that RSS documents are supposed to use. Until I can find the correct namespace to use, I can't make the feed live.

We went to see a jazz concert today. The first act was a group from one of the schools, and they were pretty good. I wouldn't mind looking up some of their songs to see if they are in the public domain, and adding them to my playlist if they are. Unfortunately, they didn't have a list of the songs they played available. The second act was hard to bear though. This group of four professionals took a bunch of known-proprietary songs that I already didn't like and butchered them. It was cool though that the saxophone player came out into the audience so we could see the saxophone being played up close. Both acts were a bit loud though and could stand to have their speakers turned down a bit.

My mother got the news tonight that she's been transfered to Millicoma Middle School like she wanted. Or rather, if she's stuck in this area, that's where she wants to be. She'd rather move closer to Portland, but life at Madison Elementary School has been pretty awful. Between a staff that doesn't support her, extra work that constantly gets piled on, and a classroom full of little monsters, she needed to get out of there.

I went through my entire weblog and fixed all the IRC URIs (again). This time will hopefully be the last time I have to do so. If we could actually get a standard put in place for these things, they would be more stable.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Beginning to file bug reports against Web browsers

Day 00369: Thursday, 2016 March 10

I broke down and tried using uzbl without Tor. However, as it won't accept "bad" certificates, I can't test its handling of SNI host names. I sorted the rest of the Web browser I tried into categories debending on the nature of the bugs that they display in relation to Host headers and SNI host names. I found that Links and Links2 were the only two without bugs! Those two don't support SNI host names, but that means that they are at least not sending malformed SNI host names.

I tried to report the bug in Firefox to Mozilla, but I when attempting to register an account, I was greeted with this error message:

User account creation has been restricted. Contact your administrator or the maintainer (bugzilla-admin@mozilla.org) for information about creating an account.

I need this bug fixed though, so I wrote to the email address provided in hopes of getting help.

Next, I went to report the bug in Midori. That seemed simple enough at first, but they wanted me to include information on what version of Midori I'm running. Seeing as every Web browser I've tested either has this bug, one of two others, doesn't support SNI, or won't start, the chances that this is fixed in recent versions is very slim. However, I didn't want my report dismissed on the grounds that I'm using an outdated software, so I looked into upgrading. The Midori team provides a package, but they also warn that installing it can lead to complications due to dependency on more recent versions of libraries than are available in the repository, so I downloaded the source instead. Before compiling it though, I decided to check the version number of my installed copy to see how far behind the most recent version it is. As it turns out, I already had the most recent version! Because Debian dropped Midori from their repository in Debian 8, I had gotten Midori from the unofficial backports repository, and the backports repository has an up-to-date copy of Midori.

Next, I tried to report the bug in Arora, but I can't find a place to do so. The main website redirects to the Github repository, but that repository seems to have its "issues" feature disabled. I ended up sending an email to the developer. He responded saying that the functionality in question is actually a part of the Qt networking library, so that is where the bug lies. I'll probably submit a bug report on Qt tomorrow.

I tried to report the bug in Chromium, but a Google account is required and Google will not allow me to register without a telephone number. I went to #Chromium for help, and found a URI mentioned in their topic about reporting bugs, so I followed it. It redirected to a page that throws 500 errors if you don't have a User-Agent string set. After I set my User-Agent string, it redirected to another Google log in page. I still couldn't report the bug without a telephone number, which is both obnoxious and counterproductive. If people want to report bugs, you should be happy to have testers, especially when you aren't even paying them, and should not demand pieces of information that they may not have or may not want to give you. I pasted my bug report somewhere where it'll be accessible for the next ninety days, then asked someone in-channel to file it on my behalf. Thankfully, ellyjones stepped up and said she'd submit the bug report for me, though she also told me something I already knew: it's unlikely that the developers will even care. However, it seems that the Chromium developers think that the bug is yet another symptom of a known bug. Looking over the details, it does indeed mention the SNI host name issue. My interference wasn't needed.

I still haven't heard back from my old school about the check. I'll likely need to write to them again on Monday.

Tonight, my mother freaked out again. She invited me to a trivia challenge event. Not wanting to deal with her and her name issues, I thought that the safest option was to decline. However, I made the mistake of trying to justify my declining of the offer. If I had simply said that I didn't want to go with no explanation, everything would have probably been fine. I said that it didn't seem like something I would enjoy, as it sounds like competition and I'm not a fan of the necessity of there being winners and losers. She replied that that it's similar to how things work in life. I continued that not everything in life is enjoyable, and competition is one of those things in life that I don't enjoy. That really set her off. It was as if she thinks that everything that's mandatory in life must somehow be fun and should be craved. It's utter nonsense.

With mother in such a mood, I really wanted to stay home and not go to the family science night. I didn't know how to tell her this without pissing her off further though, so I went anyway. As it turned out, we ended up manning different stations, so it all worked out. Vanessa and I worked a balloon booth with a stranger, while our mother worked a booth on the other side of the room. Cyrus ended up volunteering as well instead of participating as he had planned, and worked a booth near the center of the room.

Before heading off to bed, I noticed that my my hidden service port-listing function had failed to alphabetize the known port forward destinations. I fixed the function, then updated the port listing online.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I thought that this website would need to come down for a while

Day 00370: Friday, 2016 March 11

Looking through the Qt bug database to see if the SNI bug had already been reported, I found that while it hadn't been reported yet, other bugs related to SNI were already in the database. That's a good sign for me, as it tells me that I'm indeed in the right place. The Qt account signup process involved a form that requested a telephone number, so I was worried I wouldn't be able to create an account, but it turned out to be optional and I filed my report.

Someone from Mozilla wrote back about the creation of my account. He claimed that the website blocks registration based on a blacklist of known temporary email address providers. but y.st isn't a temporary email address provider! I highly doubt that this blacklist would happen to contain my domain that hardly anyone knows of. My guess is that it's either blocking me because of my Tor use, my use of an uncommon TLD, or my use of a single-character SLD. In any case, the person from Mozilla created the account for me manually, so I was able to submit the bug report.

The GNOME bug tracker also uses the Bugzilla software, but they don't seem to have any blocks in place, so account creation was simple. I submitted my bug report against Epiphany and was on my way. Filing a bug report against Konqueror was just as easy, though I kind of wonder if Konqueror's issue is inherited from Qt like Arora's is.

I couldn't find a bug tracker on the Surf website, but they did mention a channel on OFTC. The channel topic requests that people test against the Git repository before submitting bug reports, so I did that. In-channel, quinq said that they don't have a bug tracker, but that I could post in-channel or use the mailing list, then asked about the nature of the bug. Upon explaining, quinq said that the bug was probably actually in Webkit. I went to the Webkit website, and it said to download the latest nightly build before reporting bugs. However, the nightly build page would only show me the build for OS X. I submitted a bug report anyway though, and if it comes up, I'll tell them about how their nightly download page only provides an OS X version.

I tried to find an official website for the w3m Web browser, but the closest thing that I could find was their SourceForge repository. To report a bug there, I'd need a SourceForge account, but they claim that my registration violates their antispam policy. As they detected "Anonymous Proxy" as my country of origin, their "antispam" policy no doubt is anti-Tor. I've sent an email to SourceForge in hopes of getting help, or at the very least, some clarity on why my registrations are being rejected. I located their channel on IRC to ask there, and their topic confirms that their main presence is at SourceForge. The response they gave asked for my IP address, confirming that they are likely maliciously discriminating against Tor users.

I received some information via paper mail about my new dental coverage provided by the state. They assigned Advantage Dental as my dental care provider. They have a location very close to my house, but instead of assigning me to that location, they assigned me to one that will take all day to walk to. I don't see an option to contact them online either. I was going to walk into the local location when I got a chance and ask them about it, but events later in the day changed that.

It seems that I've allowed myself to become distracted again. I should have been making preparations to move out. My mother continues to act strange today and said that she wants me to move in with my father on Sunday. She started out by saying that she was headed over to her school to help with their school carnival, so I offered to help out. She then went on about how I don't like competition and so she doesn't think I like anything that she likes. Somehow, this equates to me not being a good candidate for volunteering. She then went on about how she thinks that I intentionally gravitate toward anything strange. She specifically mentioned my preferred hair style (shaved very short), my asexuality, my veganism, and my not being a driver. When I confronted her with the fact that I couldn't have chosen to be asexual, she practically told me that I should at least be in the closet about it. When I confronted her with that but using my own blunt phrasing, she amended her stance to be that I should be in the closet about it except with people I know very well, as if it's something I should be ashamed of. She also claims that the reason I don't want to drive is out of fear. If I'm afraid of driving, if it's not an environmental stance, then why am I vegan? Am I afraid of eating animal products too? She then tried to blame me for part of her own carbon footprint, claiming that if I was a driver and could have run her errands, hers would be smaller. Speaking of my veganism, she claims that it infringes on her right to have a family meal with her. However, it seems like she wants to infringe on my right not to consume animal products and not be involved in a meal that requires such consumption. When mentioning my hair, she seemed to think that I'd seen my preferred haircut on other people and tried to use it myself, but that that haircut doesn't work on me because I'm overweight. This is a huge change from her older stated stance, which is that the haircut doesn't look good at all. It's true, I'm overweight and I need to work on that. But it's not true that I tried to copy that haircut from others. What happened is that she used to cut my hair, but she got too busy to cut it for a long time a while back. I finally got desperate and bought a trimmer. After using it on myself, I found I liked the haircut a lot better than my old one. I suppose that's of little consequence though. She also said that speaking with me is like speaking to a retarded person. In any case, she said that I should go live with my father on Sunday. I don't know how to reach him about this, seeing as his old email address has recently been presumably lost due to us ending our service with our old ISP. I was going try writing to my sister to get his email new address tonight. Once in Springfield, I'd try to get my old job back, then work on getting an apartment and moving out. My mother said once I move in with him, she'll consider me a traitor and never want me to come back, though moving in with him at all is her idea. I feel devastated, though if I did manage to get my old job back, it might have been be a new ray of hope in my life. Here in Coos Bay, all I am is trapped.

I might have needed to leave my server here in Coos Bay, so I did some light planning for such. It'd be a shame, but if it came down to that, at least I'd be ready. I'd remotely wipe my onion keys from Springfield over SSH. After deleting the keys, I'd probably try to find a way to wipe all the data on the machine securely. Whether I needed to leave the server behind or not, my onion addressed website would need to go down for a time. I wouldn't have another place to hook up the server until I found my own place to live. This also means that my censorship-bypassing onion address would need to come down. I wouldn't be able to help people anonymously access IRC networks that maliciously discriminate against Tor users for a while.

My mother left for a while to work at that carnival, but when she came back, it sounded like the carnival had actually been an auction. Or maybe there was an auction at the carnival? I wasn't going to take the risk of trying to understand the situation. She changed her story, and now seems to be more on the side of helping me get an apartment than having me move in with my father. That said, she seems to have decided to potentially not have me move out yet at all. This buys me more time, but I still need to get busy and find a job and move out. Staying here is not an option, this is in no way a healthy environment for me.

I seem to be quite shaken up tonight. A friend had to fix several typographical errors in the latter half of this entry for me.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Progress has been made by Qt, but Webkit doesn't actually understand the issue

Day 00371: Saturday, 2016 March 12

I woke up this morning and found a letter in my inbox saying that the SNI bug in Qt had been labeled as important by the developers. Mozilla reclassified my bug as being a bug in their HTTP handling, which means that they are actually taking notice. Google was working on this bug before I told them about it. It's been a short period of time since I submitted these reports, but those that have taken notice actually seem to care. Both ellyjones and I thought that people would fail to realize that this is important. There are more bugs to report to other Web browsers, as well as Wget and cURL, but that will have to wait for now.

Later in the day, I received an email alerting me to a commit to Qt's code repository fixing the bug. I'm not sure if the commit is to the main repository or if this is some sort of pull request, but even if it's only a pull request, I doubt there's any reason to avoid accepting it. The code has already been written and it fixes a known problem. My best guess is that this is a pull request of sorts, as it shows a table listing different people that need to check the code and sign off on it. The commit message even shows that they are properly leaving the Host header alone while fixing the SNI error. I am so excited!

Do not send the trailing dot of a hostname as part of the SNI

The SNI extension must not include the trailing dot, even though this is legitimate for the host header.

Still later though, I received an email with bad news. The Webkit people think that I'm talking about in-browser certificate mismatch errors, not the malformed SNI host names that the browser is sending. As they didn't understand what I meant, they don't think there's a problem. Unless I can get through to them what I really mean and convince them that there is a problem, nothing will be done about it.

I applied for four jobs today, looked into three places that turned out not to be hiring, and got a lead on a job that I will be able to look into on Monday.

I learned something very interesting from sfan5 of #Minetest. As it turns out, the reason that some Tor exit nodes are able to access the freenode network isn't because freenode staff are too incompetent to implement the Tor DNS blacklist. Instead, it's because these nodes are specifically whitelisted. To be specific, IP addresses used by a VPN company called Private Internet Access are allowed to access the freenode IRC network even if these IP addresses are currently used to relay traffic from the Tor network. Furthermore, it appears that Private Internet Access is one of freenode's sponsors; the money that Private Internet Access pays freenode may very well be in part a bribe for whitelisting their VPN servers' IP addresses.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Webkit isn't the problem

Day 00372: Sunday, 2016 March 13

I checked in on the Qt pull request and found that it has been merged! If Arora doesn't have it's own SNI bug, Arora is now fixed. Additionally, the GNOME bug report has been changed again, this time to reflect that the bug is in glib and that it relates to networking in an unspecified version. People are actually looking at it and passing it to the developers of the particular subproject so that it can actually get fixed. This is better than I dared hope for! With a little luck, maybe the Webkit bug will be taken seriously as well. However, while I was out, I saw that the Webkit people are saying that the "host name/SNI mismatch" error thrown by the server is caused by the fact that Webkit is sending the correct HTTP Host header and correct SNI host name, and because one has a trailing dot and the other does not, they don't match. As I've tested what happens when you send the correct SNI host name and correct HTTP Host header, I knew that this isn't the case. I was under the impression that the "mismatch" was that the two didn't correspond with one another because the trailing dot SNI host name doesn't correspond with *any* HTTP Host header, as it's invalid. I thought that I'd have to set up my own HTTP server that the Webkit people could access, which would be a breach of my ISP's terms of service. With my own Web server, I might be able to nudge my server into providing access to my Web application by using a couple lines of code in a PHP-based 400 error page. After running into a strange error in Iceweasel that prevented me from loading the SNI testing page (Iceweasel refused to allow me to accept the "invalid" certificate), I tried a subdomain of the main testing page because the certificate specifically mentioned being valid for two subdomains. Much to my surprise, I found that not only did the new page not set off Iceweasel's anti-TLS error, it also didn't set of the server's error, despite the fact that the Web browser was still sending a malformed SNI host name. Using this to my advantage, I was able to show the show the Webkit people the malformed SNI host name sant by Web browsers using their software. By the end of the night, they did understand the problem. However, they say that the bug isn't in Webkit, but somewhere else. The person I spoke with confirmed that the error is in Safari (which I couldn't test myself), Chrome (Which I assumed had the error because Chromium does), and Firefox (which I already reported the bug in). He said he'd pass the information on to Apple so that they can fix Safari, which should lead to one more Web browser being fixed. However, it means that I still need to figure out who to report the problem in Surf to.

Speaking of playing games with the 400 error page, I found that I can display an actual page on my choosing in place of the default 400 error page, though doing so is less intuitive than I'd like. It might be possible to write a tricky 400 error page that checks to see if the cause of the error is a malformed SNI host name, and if it is, return the page that would have otherwise been returned if the SNI host name wans't present or was correct. I might use this for a Web-based game if I have time to build it. People that are running reasonable Web browsers might get a bonus while those running unreasonable Web browsers might get an inverse bonus and be presented with a link to an explanation. The explanation would provide links to the bug reports on known Web browsers and invite the user to either pressure the developers into fixing them, file their own bug report against an unlisted Web browser, or switch to a known-working Web browser.

I spent most of the day in Springfield, trying to remove a broken faucet to replace it with one that might work. However, most likely due to heavy corrosion, I wans't able to fully remove it. I'm not sure what we're going to have to do about it.

On the way home, I was thinking about moss and wondering if it's harmful to the trees it grows on. I thought that I recalled hearing that moss doesn't sap the nutrients out of trees, but the roots of the moss digging into the tree had to be doing damage. And if the moss is digging into the tree, why doesn't the tree's immune system fight off the moss? I looked it up on the way back, and it turns out that moss isn't in fact harmful to most trees and isn't a parasite. While moss does produce threadlike structures that help it hold onto the tree, it has no roots and doesn't actually dig into the tree. This probably explains why moss can grow so well on stones too. The biggest threat that moss poses to trees seems to be its weight. If a particularly weakened and/or old tree has too much damp moss on it, it might not be able to support it all and that could lead to breaking.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Retiring the spider for now

Day 00373: Monday, 2016 March 14

I followed up that job lead from a couple days ago, but it didn't go anywhere. They aren't hiring right now.

As Surf's malformed SNI host names aren't coming from Webkit, I'm now guessing that the problem comes from glib. The GNOME people seem to currently think that the same bug in Epiphany comes from glib, and like Suckless, they were considering the possibility that the bug might come from Webkit or libsoup. The people in #Suckless confirmed that this is a likely case. I reported the SNI bug in Wget. Someone from SourceForge also wrote back saying that not only would he pass the information of my account registration difficulties on to someone that would look into it, but also that he had created an account for me, should I want to use it. Using that, I was able to file the bug report against w3m. With that, I've not filed a bug report against all Web clients that I have found to have this particular bug, though there are other Web clients that I haven't tested and other Web clients with other related bugs. Tomorrow, I should report the bug in cURL, Elinks, and Lynx that causes these three Web clients to send incorrect HTTP Host headers.

I applied for five jobs today and found that three places are not hiring. I attempted to apply for a sixth job, but the website was screwy. While it did allow me to apply for two jobs, attempts to apply for a third kept getting mistaken for attempts to apply for one of the jobs that I had already applied for. Tomorrow, I think I'll leave the house and search for jobs I wouldn't think of if I didn't see them.

Working with my onion space spider is what brought me to the malformed SNI host name bug of some Web clients, incorrect HTTP Host header bug of other Web clients, and bug that causes incorrect normalization of URIs in Netsurf. Ironically, due to the fact that Tor is unable to understand onion addresses with trailing dots, the onion space spider never actually had to deal with these issues. It was only due to research that I needed to complete in order to finish work on the spider that I read the documents that led me to the problem. The onion space spider is still incomplete and no doubt still has much to teach me, but I feel that I don't have the energy to deal with both the spider and job hunting. With both the spider and the job hunt, there is a sense of urgency, and neither can be squeezed into the small scraps of time left available by the other. It's for that reason that I'm putting the spider aside for now. Until I have a source of income, the spider will have to gather dust on my virtual shelf. These bug reports won't fill my scraps of time for long though, so I may start one or more projects that are less intense and less urgent. I might work on that forum I've been wanting to for a while or I might start building a browser-based online game.

Wowaname has been experiencing trouble with a DDoS attack on her server. As a result, she (and I) seems to no longer be on the clearnet. I was notified that I was off the clearnet last night, so I imagine that wowaname was as well. I wonder why people are attacking though. Is it some random attack or is someone angry about something?

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I now know where the temp agency is

Day 00374: Tuesday, 2016 March 15

Most of today was spent out and about in town searching for jobs. Before I went out, I applied for four jobs and found that three places were not hiring. While out on the street, I found twenty-four places that aren't hiring, I handed out twelve resumes, six places told me to apply online, I obtained nine usable job applications, and three places told me to try back at certain times. I also picked up four other job applications, but due to not noticing that these applications didn't have any mention of the business that they're from, they were wasted. Probably most importantly, I also learned where a temp agency is and I'll probably head that direction tomorrow. I'm tired now though, and tomorrow will be tiring as well, so I'll likely wait until the weekend to fill out all these job applications. Additionally, I'll be sure to check the ones that I pick up tomorrow as I get them to be sure that they have the name of the business that I got them from, and if it's not there, I'll write it before I leave.

When filling out job applications that ask for a telephone number, I provide the number of the telephone line I have set up exclusively for job seeking. However, resumes are somewhat free-form, so on principle, I didn't include any telephone numbers. After all, I despise the telephone number system. However, that could lead to me not getting hired in some cases. Some businesses are set up so backwards that they have telephone access but no computer access, which would lead to these potential employers having no choice but to silently ignore my resume. They couldn't contact me back even if they wanted to! While I was out though, I found a way to make adding a telephone number to my resume somewhat tolerable. When I got home, I changed the email address to a mailto: URI and added a tel: URI. Don't get me wrong, telephone numbers are still idiotic, even in URI form. Linking to a telephone number is as bad as linking directly to an IP address instead of a domain. However, this at least keeps me pacified while still making sure that potential employers can call me if they are backwards enough to prefer telephones over email. Even if people don't recognize it as a URI, it's pretty easy to visually decipher that it's a telephone number, and the "tel:" part will likely be mistaken as just an indication that it is such a number, which I suppose in a way, it is. This change came too late to help with the resumes that I handed out today though.

I received more information from my dental health care provider about my plan via post. Speaking of my dental health care provider, I'm not sure why I thought that they had a closer office than the one that they assigned me to. The nearby dental office belongs to an entirely different dental health care provider, and one that I already knew the name of and has a name that is drastically different from the name of my own provider. That means I won't be able to talk them into allowing me to get service from this closer office.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The Wget and cURL people prefer buggy behavior over following standards

Day 00375: Wednesday, 2016 March 16

I was speaking to someone about telephone numbers this morning, so I thought that I'd post my thoughts on the matter here as well. The problem with telephone numbers is twofold. First, people are expected to enter them directly into their calling devices. This is moronic. This would be like expecting people to enter IP addresses when trying to access websites or expecting emails to be sent to "{user}@\{IP address}". IP addresses, like telephone numbers, are meaningful to the machines, but not meaningful to people. However, people are still expected to memorize these numbers. When people link to services by IP address, at least they do so because they would rather use a number than a name. They *choose* to use a number. With telephone numbers, there's no choice. There isn't an option to use a name.

As a side note, it's worth noting that when faced with the problem of telephone numbers being linked to a specific service provider and being lost if you switch service providers (just like how you lose your IP address if you switch ISPs), telephone architects took the wrong approach. It used to be that telephone numbers were like IP addresses, telling the machines where to find the call destination. Instead of adding the use a centralized-yet-somewhat-distributed name system such as DNS, telephone numbers (at least in the United States) were modified to no longer mean anything to the machines. They are now "portable", meaning that telephone numbers are looked up my the machines from a big lookup table like DNS names are. So instead of fixing the problem, it was made worse. Telephone numbers are meaningless both to humans and machines now.

The second issue with telephone numbers is that people are expected to identify by them. I don't mind identifying by a human-readable and easily-memorable email address, but in many, many systems, your telephone number is your de facto identifier, as if a telephone number means anything at all. This is ridiculous.

On the topic of malformed SNI host names, the person commenting on the Wget bug report page mentions that the problem is present in three other Web browsers, as if that makes it okay. Then, he continues that cURL strips the trailing dot off of both the HTTP Host header as well as the SNI host name, as if this other nonstandard behavior is another option to consider implementing in Wget. I ended up being sent emails from an out-of-band discussion, and it seems that a patch has been produced to fix the bug, but people are considering either leaving the bug in place or modifying the bug to behave like cURL's bug because they think that it would be somehow "more consistent" than having no bug. I'd just like to reiterate that fact. The Wget people already coded a patch, but would rather not apply it. It's not that they don't think that the issue is worth the time that it would take to fix it. They actually actively prefer the buggy behavior. As a side note, it also seems that there is an additional bug report against Firefox in regards to the issue. As the Wget people were discussing the fact that cURL also didn't implement the standards correctly, so Wget somehow shouldn't have to, I thought it best to bring up the fact that I too had noticed the bug in cURL but had not yet had the time to report it. At that point, I was pretty much obligated to report it in cURL today, but it turns out that the people that want to avoid making Wget follow the standards are in charge of cURL development. In other words, trying to get the issue fixed in cURL is a waste of time.

My bug report against Firefox has been marked as a duplicate of another bug report, but this other bug report suggests implementing cURL's buggy behavior of also stripping the trailing dot of of the HTTP Host header. This doesn't bode well.

I've come to the conclusion that I won't allow the fact that Web clients don't implement the standards to stop me from using https://y.st./ as the canonical version of my URI. I will report the error to as many Web clients as I can find and test, then wait for Debian 9 to come out. Debian releases take forever to come out, so this arbitrary deadline will give developers plenty of time to fix their software. After that, I will put my https://y.st/ to https://y.st./ redirect into place (assuming that I am able to run my own clearnet Web server at that point). cURL and any client that has a similar bug as cURL will get stuck in redirect loops until they give up. Any client that instead has the malformed SNI host name bug will either be presented with an error page (Apache's default) or will be presented with a version of the wanted page that has been modified to include an error message about the malformed SNI host name and a link to a page explaining more. I can't force people to care about their bugs or agree that they should be fixed, but I shouldn't allow their refusal to follow standards prevent me from using a completely-legitimate URI of my choosing.

Josh Woodward's campaign to raise money for his upcoming album, Addressed to the Stars, ended today. He ended up getting 426.1% of the funding that he was looking for. He always gets over-funded when he does these things. I'm not sure if he sets small funding goals out of modesty or if he honestly isn't looking for as much money as he gets. It sounds like physical item delivery is expected in April, though it's the digital music that I'm more interested in.

My goal for the day was to reach the temp agency to get information on how to register for their services. It turns out that they have their applications online only, but I now have their Web address and email address. While I was out, I also found one place that said to try back in May, found eleven places that were not hiring, found one place that I passed on because they insisted that the paper application be filled out in-store; I didn't feel I had time, found seven places that said to apply online, dropped off five resumes, picked up five applications, and dropped one application off after having filled it out.

Wowaname is back up on the clearnet, and as a result, so am I (as wowaname is currently hosting my clearnet website).

On #Volatile, z randomly started trying to convince me that everyone should release their code into the public domain. The public domain is only better than copyleft licenses when it is the only thing that exists. When it is the only thing that exists, it becomes far greater than anything else that exists now, but as long as things in the public domain can be moved outside the public domain, it is counterproductive to not not use copyleft licenses. Copyleft licenses protect our code from becoming nonfree and closed off. The public domain offers no such protections.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I'm done with this

Day 00376: Thursday, 2016 March 17

Someone writing on the cURL bug report page is continuing to justify the stripping of the trailing dot from the HTTP Host header. I thought that I was ready to just call cURL a lost cause, and continue on my way, but this inability to get through to people that standards should be followed is still getting on my nerves. It has prompted me to start making preparations for once I have control of my own clearnet website again. I've added this to the <VirtualHost/> that serves my non-onion websites:

RewriteEngine On
RewriteCond %{HTTP_HOST} ^(.*[0-9a-z])$ [NC]
RewriteRule ^(.*)$ https://%1./ [R=301,L]

This host isn't reachable from the clearnet aside from on my local network, but tests show that it functions the way that I want it to. Screw non-conforming clients. This is personal. I also built a skeletal 400 page in PHP that causes the server to send the desired pages to clients even if they send malformed SNI host names; the catch is that i intentionally didn't change the HTTP response code. Web clients will still see a 400 error code. Some testing on my mother's machine shows that Internet Explorer refuses to display the page sent if a 400 error code is present, so Internet Explorer won't be able to see my website. I might elaborate on my 400 error page script to make it insert a warning into XHTML files as well. That way viewers will see a message telling them that their Web browser is wonky and will be provided a link to a page detailing all the known Web clients with this issue and links to the bug reports. Then again, maybe I won't even use this 400 error script at all. Maybe I'll just let Apache do things the way it does by default, but provide a static 400 error page for it to send explaining the issue. Any client that erroneously strips the trailing dot off of the HTTP Host header will cause itself to go into a redirect loop. I can't help that and it's not my job to try. I'm done with this, at least for now.

I've modified the hyperlinks in the copyright sections of my pages on this site to point to the dotted version of my main domain, as well as the copyright section in the comments at the top, as both are in my main template. I've left old hyperlinks in weblog entries alone for now, mostly because it will be a huge pain to go back and modify all of these links. I'll probably do it eventually though.

I checked back with the place that told me to check back today, and there are no jobs available there. I've also signed up with the temp agency. I found that they don't actually try to match employees with jobs. Instead, they offer job listings that registered users can apply for. I've applied for three listed jobs.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Domain research becomes URI research

Day 00377: Friday, 2016 March 18

I've updated the links across my entire clearnet site, aside from the ones in the domain research section, to point to the trailing dot version of any URI pointing to a resource hosted on a server that doesn't mind trailing dots in HTTP Host headers. I've also updated the internal relative links to use the full URI of the pages they link to, including the trailing dot. The reason that I'm leaving the domain research section alone for now is that I don't want to put in the time needed to go through every link on those pages and test them all right now.

Speaking of my domain research section, I set it up at a time when domains were the main focus of my extra-curricular research. However, I'm now focusing more on URIs. In truth though, for my use case, the main appeal of having done this domain name research is because domain names are used in so many URIs. In that way, my old domain name research is really just a subset of my new URI research, so I've moved my old domain pages to their new URI research locations. Because I'm on an NGINX server that I don't have access to the configuration of, I can't set up redirects. NGINX doesn't have a system like Apache's .htaccess files. In truth though, once I'm back on my own server, I wouldn't want the redirects in place anyway. I've set up some pages at the old locations pointing to the new locations.

The new URI research section is pretty broad. Anything remotely relating to URIs that I want to post will be there. I wrote up a new page about the SNI bug, including links to all the known bug reports, most of which were filed by me. In the process, I ended up linking to the Mozilla bug report. I took the opportunity to comment on it, as this bug report mentions a potential need to avoid stripping the dot off of the HTTP Host header. I figured that it was best to include the RFC passage specifying that the dot should not be stripped in the Host header, just in case there wasn't enough support for keeping the dot. The cURL people continue to claim that their bug is a feature, though, so I'm losing on that front. I've also written a short page on valid limitations that sometimes apply, though these limitations don't apply to the SNI bug.

Very early in the day, I received an email asking me to come in for an interview with the temp agency. I thought that it meant that I had been chosen as a potential candidate for one of the jobs that I'd applied for! However, it turns out that it was just an interview that they conduct with all new applicants with the agency. I'm probably not any closer to actually being hired. However, while I was there, I did get a chance to ask about fees. I've never used a temp agency before, and they have to make money somehow. I asked if I was to pay a fee when I get hired through them, but it turns out that the employer pays that fee, not the employee.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

phpDocumentor

Day 00378: Saturday, 2016 March 19

On #Volatile, ion was talking about how hard it is to get onto the Anonops IRC network. The problem is that they ban Tor users, then allow them to use an onion address to access the network if and only if the user has an account that has permission to use Tor. Acquiring permission to use Tor requires being an active participant on the network for three days, then specially requesting it. At that point, it's a bit too late for using Tor to do some of the good that it should be doing, and Anonops knows who you are. For a group that is supposedly really big on being anonymous, they sure do hate anonymity! Really, they're just a lot of hypocrites. I've set up an onion port forward to make accessing the network over Tor possible for the requisite three days.

I figured that it was about time that I both expanded the comments in include.d and wrote up some online documentation for these classes, functions, and constants. As I wanted the comments to contain everything useful from the online documentation and maybe a little more, I looked into phpDocumentor. PHP even has a T_DOC_COMMENT token, which kind of means that that comment style is the kind favored by the developers. I got phpDocumentor running, but it seems like it has some disadvantages. The main issue is that it generates a documentation file for each named construct and another one for each code file. Because of the way PHP's autoloading works, the most effective way to define classes is one per file. In turn, my understanding is that this autoloading behavior was decided upon because of how common it was for programmers to put one class in each file. In other words, it's a very common use case that there would be no need to have separate documentation for files and classes. Additionally, I use the same convention for my functions and constants to avoid having to load functions and constants that won't be used in a particular project. Half of the documentation files generated aren't useful, and they can't just be removed, as the file documentation pages and the class documentation pages link to each other. The documentation also shows the values of all the constants. Needing to know the values of the constants kind of makes constants less valuable. Looking at the source code, the source code uses capital letters in some (though not all) HTML tags, meaning that documentation generated would need to be cleaned up before being served as XHTML. The documentation generated also makes use of deprecated HTML attributes which would also need to be cleaned up. While I can't live with the unclean code, I think I could deal with the other issues. The documentation also makes heavy use of frames, but I could pass that off of being the fault of the documentation generator and call it fine.

I tried upgrading to a more recent version of phpDocumentor, and that fixed some of the issues. The code was a lot cleaner, though the deprecated attribute was still used on one page. This page detailed errors found during documentation generation, and I think once I go through and correct the errors, the deprecated element would disappear from the file. The frame use in the new version is outright confusing and difficult to navigate though. Additionally, some navigation elements don't work without JavaScript enabled and the self-closing syntax of HTML tags is used inconsistently. Some HTML-only entities are also used, which don't seem to function correctly when use with XHTML and the HTML5/XHTML5 <!DOCTYPE>. I blame the fact that the WHATWG got all the useful information stripped from the <!DOCTYPE> declaration. They thought that stripping it down would make it easier for developers. However, in XML, only the five XML-defined entities can be used unless the <!DOCTYPE> declaration is used to pull in other entity definitions or the entities are defined within the XML file itself. With further experimentation, I came to the conclusion that I need to build my own template set for use with phpDocumentor, but the documentation on how to actually do that is missing.

I applied for three jobs, found one place isn't hiring, and tried again to apply at a place that has a broken website. The website is still too broken to make application possible.

I haven't been able to find my wallet all day. I fear that I lost it when I was out yesterday. That would really suck. Hopefully I simply misplaced the wallet here at home and it turns up soon.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I've documented the bulk of include.d

Day 00379: Sunday, 2016 March 20

I started filling out job applications, but I quickly got distracted and started working on commenting my code instead. I also logged into the temp agency website and found that I've been turned down for one job, one job is still pending, and consideration for the third job requires an interview and/or more paperwork. I wrote to the temp agency asking about how to set up the interview and/or get access to the paperwork.

Seeing as I've been unable to find any complete documentation of how to build templates for phpDocumentor, I decided that perhaps I should build my own parser for the syntax. My plan is to write up my comments, test them in the phpDocumentor, correct any errors generated, then actually generate the documentation in my own documentation generator. However, I've run into a bit of stupidity in phpDocumentor. If the first thing in the file is the namespace declaration instead of a documentation comment, it throws an error. This is utter nonsense. I place my namespace declarations on the same line as the opening <?php tag, and there shouldn't be a problem with that. The comments then begin on the second line. The namespace applies to the entire file, so in makes the most sense to include it with the opening <?php tag as if it were an extension of it. For now, I'll move my namespace declarations to below the first comment section while checking the rest of the comments for errors, but I'm not happy about it; it's ugly. I'm not sure if I'll leave the namespace declaration there when I'm done though. I might put it back where it belongs once I verify that that's the only "error" in each file's comments. On second thought, I'll continue to comply, but I'll write my disdain into the comments of every file in which I have to follow the stupid convention of commenting before namespacing. I've gone through the list of phpDocumentor tags and written up a new template for files written for include.d. I've also written up most of the documentation comments for function and constant files and some of the documentation for class files. I've looked through the revision history to find the appropriate value for the @since tag in everything but class subcomponents; I'll look into the time that each of those was added as I document each class.

My plan was to get back to job applications in the evening, but I ended up out collecting bullet shells with Vanessa, Cyrus, and our mother due to miscommunication on Cyrus' part. When we got home, it was too late to finish with the applications, so I got back to work on documenting my code.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Firefox might get fixed

Day 00380: Monday, 2016 March 21

It seems that the SNI bug patch for Filrefox might not actually do any damage, instead fixing the problem. Hopefully the bug patch is added upstream. I'd consider having a popular Web browser such as Firefox getting fixed a major victory; especially because of how many forked Web browsers would end up fixed in the process.

I started work on filling out paper job applications, but quickly ended up whisked off to Cape Blanco instead of actually making any progress. It seems that spring break begins today, and our mother wants to spend it out of the house and with her children. It's clear that trying to find a job is going to be more difficult than usual, as I won't actually have as much time at home as I should.

When we got home, I wasn't really feeling up to working on job applications any more, so I worked on documenting include.d instead. I added very bare bones documentation to my two wrapper classes that just points to where in the PHP manual to find the information. The wrapper classes just bind functions to their resource handles, so there's really no new functionality to write about. I also went through the commit history and added an @since tag to everything that didn't have one yet.

It turns out that the message from the temp agency was due to someone failing to update the system after my recent interview. No further interviews or paperwork are required for me to be considered for this position.

I think I found the domain name that I want to buy in the future. I'm not ready to make use of it yet and I'm short on funds, so I won't buy it yet. Hopefully by not mentioning the name, people won't grab it out from under me in the mean time.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Two conflicting sets of meta data

Day 00382: Wednesday, 2016 March 23

I hadn't asked about it, but wowaname said that I could add her contact information to my port forwarding service home page. After clarifying that a link to her contact information on her website was a good way to do so, I added such a link. This should provide both the benefit of providing a way to reach her in case of problems and make it less likely that her contact information needs to be updated on my site. If she updates her contact information, she probably won't think to specifically notify me, and I certainly won't be watching that page for changes. I usually just ignore contact pages when I'm not trying to reach people myself.

Josh Woodward says that he'll release Addressed to the Stars in April, next month. He sent a link to an early copy to backers, though he only sent a link for the MP3 copy, despite promising both an MP3 copy and a FLAC copy. I was mildly frustrated at first, but figured that he'd send the FLAC copy at the time of release. He might not even have them uploaded yet. If he didn't send the link with the release announcement, I could just write to him asking about it and he'd certainly send it. After a bit though, I decided to try a little URI manipulation. Woodward's file names are pretty reasonable, so I managed to guess the URI of the FLAC files on the first try.

As it turns out, we didn't go to Springfield today. We will likely go tomorrow though.

I renamed all my music files in such a way that they contain the album artist, the album name and the track title in an effort to make future sorting easier. As I learn more about how music on my divice is sorted into albums, I keep having to dump all of my files into a single directory for resorting, and when file names overlap, it adds extra steps, as I have to rename files around these name clashes. However, this lead to a new discovery. I found that my mobile is failing to read the file meta data of Josh Woodward's Space Camp. It's also failing to read the track names and album name from one of the copies of Fragmentation that I got from Professor Shyguy's USB drive. This anomaly allso seemed to only effect MP3 files, never Vorbis files. This is most significant because most of my library is in Vorbis files. If there was going to be a strange behavior like this and it wasn't specifically an issue with MP3 files, the majority of the problematic files would theoretically be Vorbis files, so this was probably an MP3-specific problem. Once more, it was time to look into how Android determines information about tracks. I use Replicant, but it inherits all this sort of code from the main Android project. I asked about this on #Android, and GenteelBen told me about a type of meta data called ID3v2. While my laptop applications were able to music file meta data, they couldn't see if ID3v2 was specifically being used in the file. With some help from jthomas on #Debian, I found Kid3. This application reads music file meta data (among doing other things), and with it, I found something surprising and frustrating: several of the files had two sets of meta data. It seems that the state of having ID3v2 and the state of having ID3v1 meta data are not mutually exclusive, and as they are in fact two entirely separate sets of data, they can and sometimes do conflict. I can't seem to find any rhyme or reason for why Android chooses one set over the other for a given file. Android seems to be able to read either, but if both are present, I have no way to know which will be used. Furthermore, even when meta data is present, it doesn't seem to used by Android in the case of certain files. If I can figure out why Android is doing what it's doing, Kid3 has the option of renaming files. It will take more effort to use than Ex Falso though, as Kid3 doesn't seem to be able to move files into directories like Ex Falso can. Instead, Ex Falso is only capable of renaming files in place.

I tried to log into Patreon today, but much to my disgust, I found that they are now maliciously discriminating against all Tor users. It used to be that they used a CloudFlare CAPTCHA wall for requests coming from a few exit nodes, but now they seem to actively block all exit nodes with these ridiculous CAPTCHAs. There was some information that I really needed to retrieve though, so I sucked it up and eventually filled out the CAPTCHA. Once past it though, I found that logging in has become impossible! I am a paying customer, they had better fix this. I can't find a good way to reach them though. I tried pinging their Twitter account, so we'll see if that goes anywhere. I suspect that they are intentionally blocking Tor users, even when we are legitimate users and pay our bills.

I spent a good chunk of the day cleaning up around the house and didn't perform any job-hunt-related activities.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Meta data understood

Day 00383: Thursday, 2016 March 24

We spent most of the day in Springfield. I thought that our primary objective was to clean up around our former residence and perhaps host a garage sale, but this wasn't the case at all. The main goal of the trip was for our mother to see her favorite tax preparers, and the garage sale didn't happen at all. We did clean up while she was away though, and she joined us when she was done. It seems that she was missing some of the information that she needed though, so she'll have to come back later. My mother was also slightly peeved that I had already filed my taxes, claiming that I should have talked to her first. I think that I talked to her, but even if I didn't, her tax preparers said that she couldn't claim me as a dependent last year. As her issue this time is that she wanted to try to claim me as a dependent, it wouldn't have helped for me to wait. It was also partially due to her insisting that I wait last year that I ended up having to file an extension. Normally, I file my taxes in February, and if she's going to put it off until March or April, I'm not going to let her drag me into that again.

I finally found a pattern to Android's choice in which meta data to use. If ID3v1.1 is present, it will be used. If not, Android will fall back to ID3v2.* if available, provided that it isn't ID3v2.4.0. If no meta data is available or the only meta data available is from ID3v2.4.0, Android won't have any information. It should also be kept in mind that if ID3v1 is found and read, it doesn't need to be complete in order to prevent IDv2 from being read. For example, if ID3v2 specifies both an album and a title but ID3v1 only specifies a title, Android won't know what album the song is a part of and will use its regular methods of filling in the gaps. With this knowledge in hand, it seems that the album artist field isn't being used after all. The separation of albums of the same name seems to actually have been caused by one of the albums not having an album name in ID3v1, so Andorid thought that there was no album, but Ex Falso was detecting the album title from the ID3v2 meta data. In fact, while Android seems to prefer the older meta data if present, Ex Falso prefers the newer meta data when present. Furthermore, it seems that the reason that this error only occurs in MP3 files because the Vorbis format isn't stupid enough to define two potential meta data sections. Without strange extra meta data, all that you have is consistency.

My laptop's battery seems to be getting worse. I don't really have the money to invest in a new one, either.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I was an idiot yesterday

Day 00384: Friday, 2016 March 25

My brother wanted Happy Parallel, and being that I got it from my Professor Shyguy USB drive, it's not nicely zipped up and ready for uploading to my server for him to download. I mean, uploading would be easy, but downloading it over HTTP would be a pain for him. To save him some effort, I tossed him my USB drive for him to use. It's kept in both its protective case and the package that it was shipped in, so when he tossed it back without the protective case, I didn't even notice. Luckily, I needed a file name off of the thing and didn't want to pull out my bulky external hard drive. He searched for the case and gave it back, but this really makes me want to avoid lending him things that I actually care about. There's not a whole lot of physical objects that I hold dear, but this is one of them.

Marc With a C seems to have a fan with cystic fibrosis that he wants to help out. She needs a double lung transplant and is hospitalized every three months for at least two weeks. Her lungs are estimated to only be functioning at twenty percent of the capacity that they should. Ouch. Marc seems to be friends with a friend of this sick fan, so he's released an album called Songs For Aubree. The premise of this album is that Marc will donate all proceeds to help pay for her medical expenses and care. It took a while to get Bandcamp to quit trying to charge me VAT (VAT wouldn't have helped pay for expenses, it would have gone to help fund a foreign government) and to get PayPal to stop being a pain in the neck as usual, but I I put in my few dollars.

It turns out that the album artist meta data is definitely being used to aid in the separation of albums by my mobile. I made a copy of some of the files and edited their meta data to check. While the inconsistent meta data reading had in fact been the cause of some album separations, some are in fact instead explained by the album artist tag. Furthermore, my statement yesterday about having found the pattern that determines which meta data will be used was made in a fit of stupidity. Two days ago, I saw that ID3v1 meta data was preferred in some files while ID3v2 meta data was preferred in others. This observation didn't suddenly become untrue, and today, I've noticed it again. I'm back to square zero as far as determining a cause of preference. However, I do now have Kid3. I don't know how the meta data for use is chosen by Android, but I can rename the files using the correct meta data when I find that I guessed wrong on the first go. When I have time, I'll compile a set of MP3 files that behave differently and document how each one behaves. After putting together a license-and-credits file, it'll be perfectly legal for me to distribute it, as my entire music library is free. If anyone is interested in helping me understand this strange situation, they'll be able to download it from this onion website, and maybe from my clearnet site.

I managed to find the separate support account for Patreon on Twitter. They don't seem to link to it themselves, you have to find it through other channels. After speaking with a representative a while and having them tell me what to try on my end, it became very clear what was going on, at least to me. There's a 403 error being thrown by one of their files. It's moronic that they use JavaScript to log in instead of a basic HTTP POST form, but their external file, probably a JavaScript file, return an error message saying that I don't pass their access control check. The server serving that idiotic external login script is in fact discriminating against me for using Tor! I am very angry. I did make sure to be very polite to the representative though, who seems to have no clue what's going on. He said that he's reached out to the engineering team, and thinks that the issue is a bug. I hope he's right and that it isn't as malicious as it looks to me. As a paying customer with no way to log in, they have my credit card information and I have no way to cancel or amend my subscription. That is not a valid business practice. This is new on their end, too. It's not like I signed up over the clearnet and later ran into this problem because I started using Tor. Instead, as a Tor user, I registered and am now cut off.

My mother asked if I wanted to pretend to be a victim again for another emergency rescue drill, but of course, I declined. She was peeved last time when I used my real name instead of the legal name that she gave me. I didn't want to fall for that trap again, and I won't operate under my legal name, which to me, is a fake name. For a bit, she tried to talk me into going, despite me being clearly uninterested, but then it turns out that she had already volunteered me without talking to me first. She thought that I'd definitely want to go and that asking was just a formality. To avoid her having to look bad by canceling, I agreed to go. When she noticed me operating under my real name still though, I'll most likely explain that this was the real reason that I didn't want to go. I didn't want to cause her grief, but at the same time, I'm not using the name that I don't identify as without just cause.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Proof that Patreon is preventing Tor-users from logging in

Day 00385: Saturday, 2016 March 26

It seems that the cause of the error when retrieving the file on Patreon for logging in is due to Patreon using a second CloudFlare-blocked domain for their scripts. I fill out their moronic Tor-discriminating CAPTCHA for their main domain, but I'm never presented with the second one, as it's not at a Web page. Basically, their JavaScript is behind a CAPTCHA wall. CloudFlare is screwy and JavaScript logins are screwy, so when you combine them, you get something even more screwy. I'm not sure if I should report this finding or not. If I do, they may just tell me to pay a visit to the second domain to fill out the CAPTCHA every time. This is not an acceptable solution. While the CAPTCHA on the main domain is not acceptable, at least it's visible. This secondary CAPTCHA that an ordinary user would never find is in even more need of fixing.

We went to the emergency rescue training to pretend to be victims of a disaster. It mostly went well, and though I was asked for my name twice, my mother was out of earshot both times and didn't suspect a thing. I ended up playing the dead victim, while everyone else had various injuries. Two injuries were fatal, though the victims didn't die until during treatment. When we were finished, they brought in pizza. I assumed that I wouldn't be eating, but it turns out that they also had salad, so there was something that I could eat after all.

I received a postal letter from Discover today asking if I'd like to open up a savings account. I don't currently have enough money to open the account, but it does sound like a good idea for the future. Discover has mostly been good to me, and I wouldn't mind doing all my banking online. I need to know if that's even possible though. How would I deposit paychecks? I've never seen a Discover branch, and I assume that they are online only. I don't use proprietary software, so if a sourceless mobile application is required, I'd have no way to deposit checks. How would I withdraw cash? I love having a card for online purchases, but in-person, I pay in cash. This isn't going to change any time soon. If having a secondary account at another institution is required for either of these tasks (for example, to deposit into the secondary account and wire it to my Discover account), it would severely limit the usefulness of having a Discover savings account. After all, what's the point of setting up an account with an online bank when an account with an in-person bank is still required? I wrote to Discover asking about these things, and they say that they'll get back to me in twenty-four hours.

I finished my documentation of include.d. (Volatile Git seems to be down right now, otherwise I would have linked to it there.) There's still much to do though. I've added several @deprecated tags in places where the proper ways of doing things haven't even been coded yet, as well as added several @todo tags. I think that this documentation in the comments should help me get more organized. I now have a very unified way of keeping track of what still needs to be done. I also now have a few different tasks that need to be completed in include.d, and I might even work on them concurrently in different branches. The most urgent task is probably getting a documentation comment parser built. phpDocumentor is ironically not documented well enough to figure out how to use, so I'll need to build my own way to build documentation from comments to get my documentation online in the mean time. Once phpDocumentor is well-documented, I'll probably switch to it. The task I'm most interested in though is cleaning up my URI class, extending it with scheme-specific classes needed for Gopher page interpretation, and fixing up my gopher() function. Last and admittedly least, several smaller cleanup and optimization tasks need to be performed, including adding more inline comments and fixing minor function input/output issues.

I received an email today about a job opening at a grocery store, so I'll probably apply for that tomorrow. I should have applied today, but I was quite eager to finish my documentation comments. Without those done, I wasn't really free to take my code in any direction. Likewise, spring break seems to have ended yesterday, so this Monday, I'll be more able to focus on job hunting, as there'll be less people around the house during the day to distract me.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Recording the past

Day 00386: Sunday, 2016 March 27

Discover wrote back saying that to get the information that I asked for, I needed to call some telephone number. I wrote to them again explaining that I don't have telephone service, but that if telephone service was required just to get basic information, that tells me that their service isn't right for me. They wrote back apologetic, but said that the information that I requested requires telephone service to access. I suppose they lost themselves a future customer then.

Ronsor came back yesterday.

I applied for work at the business that sent me a letter yesterday. I also checked in with the temp agency and found that I've been turned down for another job.

I started work on my documentation comment parser. Mainly, I just set up the initial handler for a couple of command line arguments. Actual parsing functionality will be delegated to a second file after the main file verifies that all the needed data is present. It doesn't look like I'm going to be needing to add to include.d in order to complete it though. If I do need to add something, it probably won't be much. Speaking of include.d, I set up the new branch and began work on the Gopher-related changes. First, I cleaned up the main URI class, as no forward-compatible child classes could be defined until that was done. I next cleaned up my old abstract class for URIs with a known scheme. I haven't put in any effort making sure that everything needed in that class is implemented, but I removed everything that shouldn't be there and documented the rest. Lastly, I set up an interface to implement for classes that define Gopher-indexable services. Only three classes should implement this interface, the three that are used for representing gopher:-, telnet:-, and tn3270:-scheme URIs. There's no way to lock down the interface like some built-in PHP interfaces are locked down, but even if there was, someone might find some useful way to implement it. It's a shame though that classes implementing this interface cannot be assumed to be child classes of the main URI class. The problem with implementing this instead as an abstract class instead of an interface is that this is one of potentially many specialized URI subgroups, and they may overlap. Furthermore, the fact that Gopher indexes can link to resources is only tangently-related to the URIs; this fact shouldn't be used to create a hierarchy, and an abstract class would do.

My mother somehow got set off again today, this time saying that Cyrus needs to renounce our father soon; otherwise, she may boot him from her home. This is a classic case of one divorced parent trying to turn her children against the other, and she's been doing this for years. While she was telling him off, it came to her attention that he and I only have one light bulb in our bedroom, despite having three sockets. I explained to her that two of the sockets don't work and she was pissed off that we hadn't told her sooner. I reminded her that I had in fact told her when I had discovered it, but as usual, she insisted that I had never told her and was "changing history". Thankfully, I had written about telling her in my weblog, and was able to look up the exact date in which I had told her: 2015-10-07. She seemed frustrated with me and still couldn't remember, but mostly dropped it after that. What I've learned from this is that I need to include information in my weblog on every potentially-important thing that I tell her just so I have recorded evidence.

The other day when I thought that I had had the wrong dental office when I thought that there was one nearby, I was wrong. I think that I mixed up the names of my primary medical care provider and my dental care provider. I verified online that the local dental office is in fact owned by my dental care provider. I'll walk in tomorrow and ask about if I can swich which office that I have appointments at, as they currently want me to go to a distant office that would take all day to reach, while the office that I'll visit tomorrow is just down the street. On the topic of dental care, one of my teeth has been hurting lately. While brushing my teeth today, the pain sharply increased, and I can now see a large hole in it. Last time that I knew, I had some damage on that tooth, but no large holes; just a couple of grooves. My mother says it looks rotted out from the inside, so my best guess is that the grooves deepened, the inside rotted out, and while brushing my tooth tonight, the thin remaining outer layer broke off. She says that I'm going to lose that tooth, and I don't doubt it.

I managed to find my wallet today. I had been starting to panic about it. While I had been almost certain that I had brought it home at first, I was starting to doubt whether I had actually managed to get it home more and more. If I had dropped it while I was out, there was zero chance that I'd be getting it back; I don't keep identifying documents in that wallet, only cash.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

To lie to medical professionals

Day 00387: Monday, 2016 March 28

I received a letter from one of my credit unions today saying that if I got an automobile insurgence quote, they would ship me a gratis umbrella. In the fine print, they said that the offer is only valid if I get the quote over the telephone. That's just moronic. There's no valid reason to require that a quote be obtained over the telephone.

I want to speak with the people at the dental office, and I think I may have somehow looked up the wrong dental office yesterday. I swear that the address I saw was on Virginia avenue, but the only dental offices there are with other providers. Luckily, a local office was available, and perhaps it was even slightly closer than the office that I thought was the right one; it was just about half a block off Virginia Avenue, on Broadway. They said that it was in fact possible for me to set up an appointment at the local office instead of the distant one. But while emergency appointments are available for people with a pain of at least a six, ostensibly on a scale of zero to ten, as far as regular appointments, the soonest that they can see me is May 23. I'm wasn't even sure that I'll be in the city anymore in May, so I didn't set up the appointment. I later spoke with my mother about this, and she told me to lie about the pain, saying that it was of level nine and that the pain is nearly unbearable. This seems like a very bad idea. Even ignoring the fact that this would be lying, it misinforms the medical professionals that are performing work on my body. If they think that things are worse than they are, yes, they'll see me sooner, but they will also take more drastic action or potentially even the wrong action. Lying to medical professionals just isn't safe. I suppose I'll walk to the distant office tomorrow and try to make an appointment there to see if I can get a sooner appointment. If I can get a sooner appointment, even if it's at the more distant office, maybe that will appease my mother. If a sooner appointment isn't available at the other office, maybe I'll suck it up and tell her about my fears with lying to the dental people. Alternatively, maybe I'll just schedule the May 23 appointment if I can't get a sooner one at the other office. If I have to cancel it, I have to cancel it.

I worked on include.d a bit, but I quickly hit a snag: PHP traits can't define class constants. This throws a wrench in my usual method of setting exception codes. For the built-in exception classes, exception codes are integers. To make such numeric information meaningful, I set up class constants to compare the exception codes to. That means to see if an exception was caused by a particular exception-throwing case, you can compare the exception code to the relevant constant. This doesn't help if you don't have any guesses as to where the exception came from, but you usually do have a pretty good idea of what could do the throwing based on what code you wrote and/or interfaced with, and this is the closest that I can get to meaningful exception codes in the default exception classes. Now I'm faced with several options, assuming that i can't come up with any better ones. I could have the class that uses the trait define the constants, but that would mean that each class that implements the trait would have its own set of constants to check against. You wouldn't have a generic way to check to see if the exception was thrown by a particular method; instead, you'd be checking to see if it was thrown by the combination of the method itself and the class that used the trait. I could set this up as static functions that return the values that would have otherwise been constant values, but that seems hacky. I could define a constant array outside of a class that is used strictly to hold the constant values that would otherwise be stored in trait constants, but that presents a couple issues. First, it doesn't take care of the constants used to provide access to the value that the __FILE__ keyword references from within the trait's file. Second, it causes all exception-throwing cases in which this external constant is referenced to be fatal if the exception's file has not been required. Then again, this may be fine. Code that isn't ready to deal with these potential exception cases by including the constant is probably not wrapped in a try block. Exceptions should be fatal when unexpected. Still, it seems messy, as you may try to catch anything that can possibly be thrown, only to have the undefined constant error kill your code. Perhaps I just shouldn't use an exception code or should use a code that's arbitrary but easy to calculate. I did some experimenting and found that I can cram six characters into a thirty-two bit integer if I use a forty-character alphabet. It's also worth noting that I still can only cram six character into the integer if I use a twenty-six character alphabet. In fact, in order to cram in a seventh character, I have to drop to a twenty-three character alphabet. If I go with this method, which is more helpful, one extra character in length or seventeen extra characters in the character set?

My mother was looking at something that she wanted online today, and it was sold out. It got me thinking. Things that she wants are often either sold out or expensive. She herself even says that she has expensive tastes. The problem is that her tastes are so popular, that people are able to charge more, and if they don't, none of the object in question are left for her to buy. Maybe this is just a symptom of how extreme of a conformist she is though. She is against rocking the boat or doing anything that could be remotely perceived as strange. Maybe she is exceeding generic at her core. I suppose there's nothing inherently wrong with being generic, as long as you aren't trying to pressure everyone else into being generic with you, as she does.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

There is no way to win with her

Day 00388: Tuesday, 2016 March 29

My mother has come to the conclusion that my journal is an attack on her, and that I write in it only so use against her. First of all, most of the content of my journal has nothing to do with her. Second, I wasn't trying to attack her yesterday with the entry I found, I was trying to defend myself! I swear, she's more paranoid than even I am in some ways. Next, she was insisting that I may have told her, but that I hadn't gotten her attention, so she didn't hear. I said nothing until she pressured for more information about the entry, at which point I explained that it said that she had come in to take a look at it. At that point, she said that she may have taken a look at it but had been too stressed to remember. She was still taking my recording of the event to be an attack though. I promised that I wouldn't bring up passages from my journal again to her, then asked if I could have her sign off that I'd told her things if I asked her too. She said that the only thing that she'd sign if i asked for her to sign off on having been told is an eviction notice. In other words, I'm not allowed to defend myself whatsoever. Whatever she says happened goes, even if she's dead wrong. Likewise, she told me off for standing up for Vanessa, which I often do when mother has screwy ideas in her head and is telling Vanessa off for no good reason. Apparently, I can't defend my sister either, as defending is interpreted as an attack against the attacking party, our mother. This living situation is horrid, and I need to get myself out of it. I need to find a job and move out.

I spent the productive part of my day visiting what I thought were the local offices of my dentist. I looked up the addresses again online before heading out, finding three locations in North Bend, and found that I was on the correct website yesterday when I saw the Virginia Avenue address. However, that address doesn't actually have an office run by my dental health provider. While I was looking for Advantage Dental, this office was run by Above Dental. Furthermore, the location will soon be run by Apple Dental, which again, isn't Advantage dental. So why does Advantage Dental have this address listed as one of their offices? The second location was the one that I'd visited yesterday, so I passed it by. The third location was also not actually an Advantage Dental office. This time, the office was owned by the Woodland Dental Clinic. Why in the world are two out of the three Advantage Dental locations listed on the Advantage Dental clinic not actually Advantage Dental locations? After I explained the situation, aside from the fact that I was trying to get an earlier appointment by visiting several locations, the woman at the Woodland Dental Clinic called the Advantage looked me up on her computer. Apparently, the Woodland Dental Clinic and Advantage Dental are either on the same computer system or can at least retrieve information from each other's systems. Maybe all the local dental practices can do that. In any case, even after having spoken directly with an Advantage Dental representative in person yesterday about setting up an appointment at the local office, The Coos Bay office was listed as being the one that I was supposed to visit, so the woman at the Woodland Dental Clinic telephoned Advantage Dental and got that cleared up. I think at this point, it might be a bad idea to try getting an appointment at the original Coos Bay location, so I gave up on that plan. On the way home, I walked into the local office and set up my appointment there. On May 23, I will see the dentist if we are still in the area.

My mother asked how my tooth was doing, so I told her that it was fine. The fact is, it wasn't hurting at the moment. The pain comes and goes. She interpreted this to mean that I had somehow managed to kill the tooth, so it wasn't going to feel pain any more. I'm not even going to bother trying to set her strait on that. She seems very much of the opinion that the pain is one of the main problems with the damaged tooth, but I disagree. The pain is a warning of the problem. With her thinking that it's done hurting though, maybe she'll worry less. Additionally, maybe she will just forget about or drop her plan to have me try lying to the dentists. It was stupid of me to tell her about the toothache in the first place. I need to learn to keep my mouth shut.

I decided not to use either of the data-packing schemes that I came up with for exception codes yesterday. The problem with them is that they don't make full use of the thirty-two bit integer range. Some thirty-two bit integers wouldn't translate to actual information. It's already the case that most sixty-four bit integers won't translate to error strings, but that's just the cost of making my code compatible with thirty-two bit platforms. I shouldn't waste what space I have in the thirty-two bit range though. Additionally, translating the thirty-two bit integer back into a readable error code on a thirty-two bit platform while using a twenty-three or forty character character set seems like a nearly impossible task without the GMP extension. If I use a character set that allows me to break the integer directly on lines between bits, the task becomes much more manageable. Now I just needed to decide what size I want my character set to be. Any remaining bits left over that can't be translated into full characters can be used to store binary flags of some sort. Using four-bit bit characters, I have a sixteen-character character set to work with. I woulnd't have even a full alphabet, but I'd have eight-character error strings to work with. If I use five-bit characters, I have a thirty-two character character set to work with, which would give me every capital ASCII letter to work with and either some digits or some punctuation. I'd have six-character strings with two flag bits. With six-bit characters, I'd have five-character strings, again with two flag bits. I'd also have a sixty-four character character set to work with. The obvious choice in character sets would be the base sixty-four character set specified by RFC 4648. That would give me all fifty-two ASCII letters, all ten digits, slashes, and plus signs. That's about the upper limit on character set sizes. Adding another bit would provide a one hundred twenty-eight character character set, but there's not enough printable ASCII characters to make use of the full space. The available space is far too limited to include Unicode characters. Five-bit character, six-character codes and six-bit character, five-character codes seem like the best options. Both options provide two extra bits to use as flags, so why not use both? The first flag can be used to determine if the exception was thrown from a function/method or from user code. The second flag can be used to determine if the numeric error code represents a string using a five-bit character character set or a six-bit character character string.

I set about building the functions that implement what I described above, but I found that they don't work when I use the "function/method" flag, my exception code strings can no longer be translated back from integers. Instead, they end up translated to new strings. It took me forever to track down the bug. For some reason, I thought that signed integers behave in a very strange way bitwise when dealing with negative numbers. This isn't the case at all, and they actually behave very consistently and in exactly the way that I thought that they should be implemented. I have no idea where I got the screwy format from that I thought that signed integers use. In any case, fixing this is going to be a pain. PHP doesn't have a concept of unsigned integers, which would make stuffing values into integers easy. Likewise, PHPs signed integers vary in length depending on platform. I can't depend on them to be of a particular size. I'm probably going to have to work arround this with some funky conditional padding. If positive, I need to pad with zeros, if negative, I need to pad with ones. The padding will likely have to be done with a bitmask that is obtained by taking -1 and removing the least-significant thirty-one bits. It seems like this is going to be a headache.

Some people are trying to build a community at #Lisp on Volatile, so I've been hanging out there to provide another nick for the list and act as a greeter. I've been talking about my attempts to store strings in integers there because it's programming-related, so it's somewhat-tangent to Lisp. There's not enough people there to have regular discussions on Lisp yet, so I figured it might get people talking. I mentioned the unreliability of integer lengths, which made devnull question if I was even speaking about Lisp, as PHP is probably one of the few languages that even has this issue; it's unlikely that Lisp does. Upon explaining that I was using PHP and not Lisp, z said that the solution was to switch to Lisp. I brought up my need for real name spaces and asked if Lisp had them, so he gave me a link to what I think is a Lisp name space module. This tells me that Lisp doesn't have name spaces in the core language, but this module might fix that. I don't understand the module though, so I'm not sure if it provides what I need. I think I'd need to learn Lisp before I can understand the module enough to know if it fits my needs. I suppose I'll add learning Lisp to my to do list, though I really don't have time to work on that right now. It'll have to wait.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Tor Project tee-shirt

Day 00389: Wednesday, 2016 March 30

The Tor Project sent me an email saying that I qualified for one of their tee-shirts for having run a fast Tor relay for two months! I didn't think that my connection was fast enough for that. I figured I wouldn't qualify without an exit, at least not on a consumer-grade connection. (Running an exit on certain ports cuts the speed needed to qualify in half.) It seemed to be an automated email. I've written back with a desired shirt size and color, so we'll see how they respond.

While filling out job applications online today, I ran across a PDF application that couldn't be filled out in a regular PDF-viewing application. It simply didn't have the necessary fields. It's a major pain in the neck to open these forms in the GIMP, add text, then try to get something printable out of it, so I looked into other options this time. What I found was Xournal, which allows you to type on or even draw on PDF files, among other things. This is a very handy tool to have around.

I managed to implement thirty-two bit signed integers using bigger signed integers. After the work done yesterday to try to repair my functions, only about three lines of code were needed to fix the string-to-integer function. The reverse function was already working. It was less of a pain than I thought and theoretically will provide consistent results across any platform in which PHP uses an integer size of at least thirty-two bits. Currently, I think that that's only thirty-two bit and sixty-four-bit platforms, but it should work in future one hundred twenty-eight bit platforms as well. Of course, if PHP is running on some system that causes the integer size to be sixteen bits or something, my functions will fail, as they're trying to back more data into the integer than it can hold. Speaking of which, I wonder if there's a way that I could compress the data to store even more ... I've implemented the new exception codes in the URI-related code, but I'm going to hold off on implementing them in the rest of include.d, as I may end up making other branches that focus on some of the other code later and I don't want to cause any Git conflicts. Ironically though, I'm one file away from merging the Gopher branch. If I don't start focusing on other parts of the code, I'll be finished with this branch soon, but if I do start working on other things, it'll slow the completion of this branch and make it more likely that I'll be starting another branch. I'll probably start working on maintenance tasks such as that in this branch after I finish with this branch's goals, so I will be free to merge with master at any point that I need to. I've also added the two most basic scheme-specific classes and fixed up the Gopher directory-parsing function to handle Gopher+ directories and delegate port normalization to the URI classes. I've officially set up include.d's first release too, though this release is of the pre-Gopher-branch version of the master branch.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Strange DNS server and IRC server issues

Day 00390: Thursday, 2016 March 31

When I awoke today, I found that the power had gone out and come back up. It took my Tor relay down with it, and for some reason, Tor didn't come back up when the machine did. Looking into the issue, irc.freenode.net wasn't resolving, so Tor was claiming that the domain couldn't be parsed. Again, this had noting to do with parsing and everything to do with resolution. It'd be nice if there was some sort of way to tell Tor to ignore certain addresses if they can't resolve instead of refusing to start at all, but even if that feature isn't added, Tor should be fixed to give an appropriate error message. In any case, my instance of Bind9 was somehow failing to resolve irc.freenode.net. I have no idea what the problem was. The failed resolution message was distinct from a missing record response. While requests for ircs.freenode.net resulted in an NXDOMAIN response, requests for irc.freenode.net instead mentioned something about truncation. The problem hadn't resolved itself by the time that I went to bed, so I tried restarting Bind9. That fixed the issue right away. It's odd that that solution would have worked though. After all, I didn't notice the problem until right after the server had restarted, meaning that Bind9 had *just* restarted. If that didn't fix it, why did a second restart work? Speaking of unexplainable issues, the server losing power also took down ngIRCd. ngIRCd didn't come back up with the server as it was supposed to, so I assumed that there was some sort of configuration issue. Most likely, I had modified the configuration and forgotten to restart the software, so I didn't notice that the new configuration was bad until the whole machine restarted. However, that wasn't the case at all. Without making any configuration changes, simply telling the machine to start ngIRCd back up worked. I'm at a loss as to why it didn't bring ngIRCd back up of its own accord.

Yesterday, I forgot to set up the parts on my known_scheme class that enforce the presence or lack of presence of URI components based on whether a given scheme requires or disallows said components, so I set that up today. While dealing with that, I found that phpDocumentor is unable to parse files that reference values within a constant array. It's totally fine with such arrays being defined, but it acts up if you try to actually make use of the defined arrays. I ended up separating the class constant arrays into five separate class constants, which is probably a better design anyway. Constant arrays are most useful outside of classes, where there's nothing else to bind the values together. I also set up an exception code registry to make sure that I only use each exception code in one place. Using unique exception codes doesn't hurt and it could be useful for debugging. As sort of a way to document why include.d doesn't define an autoloading function, I added an implementation of \__autoload() that checks for things that would prevent the \spl_autoload() from loading classes from include.d, fixes them, then makes sure that \spl_autoload() has been registered as an autoload function. It additionally calls \spl_autoload() or \spl_autoload_call() if necessary. Using default settings, aside from a modified path that includes include.d, calling \spl_autoload_register() with no arguments is all that's necessary for setting up the default autoloader to load classes from include.d. I thought that I could finish with the gopher:-scheme URI class today as well, but I ended up entirely scrapping the previous work that I'd done on that class from when I first started building scheme-specific URI classes. I might end up scrapping my https:- and http:-scheme classes as well. I've made major improvements to the parent classes, and the child classes might not be salvageable.

While continuing with the job hunt today, I found a couple of oddities. First, the theater was closed, so I couldn't drop off that particular application. Why would they be closed during normal business hours? Even stranger though, I found that for a dog grooming position listed online, a year of dog grooming was required. However, for a position involving care of people, experience is only preferred, not required. So ... people are pickier about who grooms their dogs than who takes care of the elderly or otherwise incapacitated? If I were in need of care, I'd find that a bit insulting. I wouldn't be demanding people with experience or anything, but it seems like the dogs are being given priority.

My mother asked about when my dental appointment was, which I was really hoping that she wouldn't do. I had to admit that while I had tried to get an earlier appointment, it wasn't a possibility and my appointment was on May 23 as I had originally told her. She said that I shouldn't lie to the dentists and tell them that I'm not in major pain. She said that it doesn't accomplish anything for me to try to tough out the pain. Okay, it seems that she doesn't actually thing that I killed my tooth after all, as she thinks that it's in excruciating pain. I'm a bit less frustrated with her now though. She hadn't been trying to get me to recklessly lie to the dentists in an attempt to rush my care. Instead, she was just failing to listen, as always, and didn't realize that when I said that I'm not in major pain, that it meant that I'm not in major pain. In fact, unless I bump that spot on my face hard enough or I get something in the hole in my tooth, I can barely feel that there's a problem. It certainly isn't painful most of the time. I explained that to her, and she finds it strange that a hole that big doesn't hurt more, but she dropped the subject. When she drops things, she often doesn't drop them for long though, so I may not have heard the end of this.

My mother says that she's taking a CPR class soon, and offered to take me with her. I'm reluctant to go into such a public setting with her, but I agreed to go. While the chances of knowing CPR coming in handy are exceedingly small, the possibility of potentially saving even one life would be worth it. While the knowledge will be valuable, I'm less interested in the certification that the course allegedly offers if it requires use of my legal name. Because my mother is a pain about me using my real name instead of my legal name, I think that my best bet is to leave my state-issued ID at home. Hopefully, it won't be needed, but if it is, leaving it behind prevents my legal identity from being tied to it. I'm kind of hoping that the certifications don't come with names though. However, to be honest, the chances of that don't look good. The certificates that I see online do have a name field. This training will likely be this Sunday, but we don't have the exact date right now.

I received a letter from Brad of Brad Sucks. Apparently, it's been about a year and a half since he's sent anything to people on his mailing list. In fact, I had forgotten that I was even on the guy's mailing list because he never sends anything. This is a guy that won't fill your inbox! Anyway, it seems that he's quit his non-music jobs and is focusing only on music now. It sounds like he's been hard at work on his next album, so that might be coming out at some point in the near future.

Copyright © 2016 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.